Another problem that you might run into is the incorrect casting of pointers.
A pointer can point to anything but when you need to access the actual data at the address to which
it points you may need to cast the pointer to the correct data type.
Costs are placed in parentheses like this.
This costs the generic pointer returned by Kellock to a pointer to type called my struct in my code.
That's a struct that I type left.
Now bear in mind that when you cast one type to another you're not actually changing one type to another.
What you are doing is giving an instruction to the compiler telling it that you know that the thing
you are casting will be of the type you are casting it to.
So if you go ahead and for example use a pointer to get at the fields of a specific structure.
Well that's OK the compiler shouldn't treat it as an error without custom p.
In this case the compiler only knows that it's a pointer to something.
It could be anything.
Your cost tells it to a point specifically to my struct struct.
From now on it's your responsibility as the programmer to make sure that is really what it points to
the compiler assumes you know what you're doing.
So you had better make sure you do to remember that the cost is not something magic that converts one
type to another type.
It's an instruction to the compiler to let you treat one type as another type but if you now go ahead
and point P yet something that is not in my struct while the compiler is not going to help you out your
program will in all probability just crash.
It's entirely up to you to make sure that the type you cast to is the type that your code will actually
use.