Pointers out of scope are definitely things to avoid.
Look here I've declared an array of chars which is initialized when the user enters a name.
Then I just return the array.
And here I print the returned name from it.
And my name except this doesn't work.
Instead of the name I entered I just see some random characters.
So why is that is because the variable b was local to the function.
It's an array which is an address and the return value of the function is that address.
But as B is a local variable its data is stored on the stock.
The stock remember is an area of memory that stores local variables but once the function exits the
stack is in effect clean up.
Data is not retained for later use.
Now let's have a look at this in code light to see if we get the same results.
Code right.
With the new compiler turns out to be a bit more helpful in this case let me run this and you can see
what happens.
OK.
So it shows me that the function returns null
by the way if you using code light or another ID with a builtin terminal emulator you may want to turn
off that option to use the commom the standard command prompt.
I mean code like to do that with settings preferences terminal and I would just uncheck this and it
would use the standard system prompt.
I'm going to leave this check for now because there is another work around.
Now let me explain first why why I suggest that this is something that needs to be done.
It's because the terminal uses buffering and that may prevent text from appearing immediately in the
built in terminal when you print a string and then go on to prompt you to enter something.
Now this is my alternative workaround because I am actually using the built in terminal.
So before I print and start reading strings to and from the terminal I add this line of code
and now that deals with the buffering it turns the buffering off so that when I enter and text it doesn't
cause any problems.
But if you do get problems either use the system terminal instead of the built in terminal or use that
workaround by adding this line of code.
Now at any rate whether you see this Mac message the that code like shows showing that NULL was returned
or you see the one the Microsoft compiler is that's the Microsoft compiler showed where some random
characters are shown.
So those are the two possibilities.
Either way it's clearly not desirable state of affairs.
It's a bug.
And that's because to clarify again the variable b reference is an array whose scope is within the function
and only within the function which is declared.
So even though the array B is correctly initialized and the syntax used for returning a pointer to the
address of that array is correct by the time I leave the scope of the function down here in main the
array to which the pointer returned by.
The problem for function that that array the one that was referenced by that it can no longer be accessed.
And that's why there is a problem.