A point or that set to now doesn't point to any usable memory.
So if I try to use that pointer I'd be in deep trouble.
Here's a simple example.
Point B is a sign.
No.
And down here I tried to assign some data.
When I run the program home it instantly blows up.
And what should happen with just about any C-compiler on my desktop computer.
So you'll be able to find and fix this sort of problem straight away even more so if I run this in the
debugger and you can see exception thrown and it gives me details here.
B was now BTR null pointer and it tells me there's a right access violation so I can find and fix that
straight away.
However if you happen to be programming microcontrollers without virtual memory management an error
like this might not be so obvious.
In fact in that case it'll probably be quite difficult to find and fix this error is sometimes called
dereferencing a null pointer.
Once again the error is obvious.
In my sample code.
But it may be far more difficult to track down in a long and complex program.
Dereferencing a null pointer is a serious bag and you should take great care that you never do it.