So what exactly is a list.
Let's go back to my spreadsheet to explain this.
This is how we can think of an array an array of five elements is like a row of spreadsheet cells.
Each cell represents a chunk of memory sufficient to hold a single element of a certain type say 4 bytes
of memory per integer or however many bytes of memory needed per struct before I add any elements to
my array.
I have to allocate enough memory to hold a fixed number of data items.
Each chunk of memory for each item in the array starts with the previous chunk of memory ends with one
element following the next but a linked list isn't like that at all with a linked list.
I don't allocate a fixed block of memory in advance.
Instead I allocate memory on an element by element basis.
If I create a list the contains two elements.
I allocate just enough memory to hold two elements.
If I now want to add a third element to the list I allocate another chunk of memory for that new element
and then add it to my list.
But since I'm adding and maybe deleting elements at various different points of my program there locations
in memory are likely to be all over the place.
They don't occupy a single sequential block of memory like an array.
So I just can't iterate through them through the memory by counting along a certain number of bytes
as I did when using pointer arithmetic or by using array indexing with square brackets.
How then does element 1 in my list know where element 2 can be found.
The answer is that it keeps a pointer to element to the pointer stores element two's address.
So if I know where element 1 is I can use the pointer in Element 1 to find element 2 from element 2.
I can use a pointer to find element 3 and so on.
That's a bit like having non-adjacent cells in a spreadsheet in a spreadsheet.
I can access another how.
For example if I'm writing a formula to do a calculation by using its location data is the address of
the cell in the spreadsheet.
For example in my spreadsheet the integer 2 that you can see here is stored at the address.
B 3
and I can enter the address to go to.
So
you can see it's moved to highlight this double lined Square.
Shows the cell that is currently active is so at be 3 and that's kind of how a linked list works in
C except in C.
A struct in a list can contain both its data say an integer.
Under Ponta that gives the address of the next struct in the list element.
One might be a struct that contains a pointer to element to element to has a pointer to element 3 and
so on.
Let's now look at some C code to see how this can be done in a program.