This is my sample project showing a double dealing list.
I've already created a head structure with pointers that will point to the first and last elements in
my list at the outset.
These pointers go nowhere.
They just point back to the head struct itself because that's how I initialize them.
They point to the address of head.
Now I'm going to draw this out in my spreadsheet so that it will help you to visualize what's going
on here.
I warn you in advance that this is going to be quite a difficult lesson but it's an important one.
You may need to watch this video more than once and run the code and maybe also draw your own diagrams
in order to understand fully how this works.
So let's get started.
This is how the pointers of head are initialized.
They point they contain the address of the head structure.
Now let's create the list.
When I create a new struct I use this temp variable.
Here the data that each strip contains is just an int for the sake of simplicity but it's the punters
that are important.
Now I assign head next to temp's next pointer.
This makes it point to the head struct because that's where the head next pointer points at the moment
both the head next and head prev pointers point to the head struct itself.
Then I make the head struts next pointer point to my new temp struct.
That's the struct I'm initializing at the moment.
Then I set the temp struct prev pointer to point to head and here's the really tricky bit.
I use the next pointer to get at the next element and I set the prev pointer of that element to point
to the temp struct.
Let's look at this carefully.
Temp.
Next points to head.
So I end up making this assignment to the prev pointer of head and I assign the new struct temp to the
prev point of head.
So this is now the situation
now I have just one element in my list both it's next and prev pointers point to a special structure
called head that keeps track of the start and end of the list.
But as there's only one element in the list head next and head prive both point to the same element
and let's see what happens when we add another element later this time is the integer 1 temp.
Next is head next head.
Next points to the previously added element.
So that's where the temp next pointer now points like this
head next point is set to point to the new Strutt 10.
10 prev is set to point to the head struct.
Finally temp next prev.
Now let's work that out.
Ten next points to the struct we lost added to the list.
I called this pointer.
Next because I'm treating the most recently added structure as the start of my list.
Conceptually the last item I add always becomes the first element in my list and so the next element
is the one that was added before it which in my spreadsheet is the one shown above it.
So the prev point of that struct.
The one I added before creating this new struct that we are now updating.
OK so it's prev pointer is now set to point to temp
the prev point of the newly added struct always points back to the head struct.
That indicates that this struct is at one end of the list because it's prev pointer does not point to
another list element.
However its next pointer points to an adjacent struct in the list.
This may look a bit confusing at the moment but if we add another struct you'll see that there is a
pattern here.
Let's see what happens when we add a third struct.
This time its data is to its next pointer points to head next head next currently points to the previously
added struct.
So its next pointer also points to the previously added struct head next is set to point to this new
struct and temp prev is set to point to head.
Finally we set temp next prev that see temp.
Next point to the previous struct in the list.
So we are setting its prev pointer to point to the newly added struct like this.
You should by now see that a pattern is gradually emerging.
Let me read color the next and prev point to our rows here.
To clarify that can you see you know that every time a new struct is added its next pointer points to
the struct that was added before it in the list its press pointer points to the struct added after it
in the list.
So for simplicity we can think of the last item here the one that contains the int 2 as being the start
or the head of the list.
And the first item I added the one that contains zero we can think of that as being at the end or the
tail of the list.
So starting with this I can navigate through the list using its next pointer to get to this struct and
then its next pointer to get to the struct.
I see that its next pointer points to the head struct.
So I know I've come to the end of my list if I go backward through the list I start with this struct
the one that contains 0 and I call the press pointers one by one until I get to the other end of the
list.
That is the struct containing to.
Prev pointer points to the head struct.
So I know I've arrived at the end of the list and that's exactly what I do in these two wild loops in
the forward moving loop.
I start with head next.
That's the struct containing the two.
And I trace through all the next links to 1 0 until I get to head again in the backwood moving loop.
I use had prev to start with a struct containing zero Updyke trace through all the private links.
0 1 2 and 2.
I arrive at a pointer to head and that's the end of the list.
Now let me run this code so you can see the output.
I also print the addresses that are appointed to here.
You may want to stare at those later on to see how the pointers reference the struct addresses.
Compare this with my diagram in the spreadsheet
so you can see that when I trace forward I start with a struct containing 2 and I use the next pointers
to traverse the list in one direction and when I go backward I start the struct containing zero and
I use the prev pointers to traverse the list in the other direction.
I can easily find the struct at either end of the list.
Since the heads press pointer points to one end in my code I can think of that as the tail end of my
list.
The next pointer points together and one that I've chosen to think of as the start of the list.
Now bear in mind that talking about beginning and end are the first and last items in a doubly linked
list it's purely a matter of convenience unlike a linear array a list does not have an intrinsic sequential
order if you like you could treat this record the one containing 0 as the start of the list and this
record the one containing 2 as the end and you could rename the prev and next pointers to indicate that
relationship.
But there's really no first or last element as they're all linked to one another in both directions
and the list can be traversed in either direction.
The important thing to know is that the two pointers in each struct are used to navigate to the struct
on either side of it like this the terminating struts the ones at the end of the list of pointers.
Here they are either next or prev that point back to the head struct like this.
And the two pointers in the header struct point to the strikes at either end of the list so that you
can easily navigate through the list from either end.
So now we know how to create a doubling Clyst we need to find out how we can actually use it.
And I'll explain that in the next lesson.