A stock is another very important type of data structure whereas a Q is a first in first out structure
where the first thing that's handed to the queue is also the first thing that's taken off the queue.
A stock is a last in first out structure.
The last thing that is the thing you most recently added to the stack is the first thing that's taken
off it.
So if I treat a pile of playing cards as a cue I'd build it up by adding cards one by one like this
ace of spades 9 of clubs Jack of Diamonds six of spades Queen of Hearts.
And when I want to take cards from the cue I take off the one I did first.
Well that was the ace of spades.
And then the next one on so on.
But if this was implemented as a stock I wouldn't do that.
A stock is last in first out last card I did was the Queen of Hearts.
So that's the first one I take off.
Then the one I added before that.
And so on down through my stock another way of thinking this is like a stack of plates you build up
the stock by adding more plates on top of it.
And when it's time for dinner you take the last plate you are the first then the next one and so on.
So think of a cue as a bit like a line of people waiting to go to the cinema.
First come first served the first to join the queue is also the first to leave the queue.
But this stock is like a stack of plates.
The last to be added to the stack the plate right at the top is the first to leave it.
It's the first plate I take off the top of the stack when I'm ready for my dinner.