Often when you add or delete items to and from a list you do so in strict sequential order that is you
odd or delete the item from one end of the list then the next item and so on.
We've already seen how to do that with cues where you add items at the end of the queue and you take
items from the front of the queue and with stocks where you add items on the top and take them off the
top as well.
But what happens if you want to delete an item from the middle of a list or at a specific index in the
list.
Well that's a bit trickier because you need to deal with any pointers from the elements on either side
of the deleted item if you just delete an element the punters the previously pointed to it.
Now Punkte to some random bit of memory you need to make sure that deleting an item does not break the
links in the list.
You have to rewire the pointers in the elements on either side of the deleted item to make sure that
they point to valid elements in the list.
And this program I build a list.
In this case containing five elements and ask the user to enter an index.
My aim is to delete the element at that specific index.
This is done by passing that index to my remove function.
And let's see what that does.
It gets the first item just as we've done in several other programs then this do while loop iterate
over the queue until I get to the element at the index I'm looking for when I equals position and position
is the index is entered by the user and I return that item and then down here
so down here the returned item is not now.
That is if it's a valid element then I free it.
OK so finding an item at a specific index and freeing its memory is pretty straightforward.
But if I freed its memory when the item was still part of the list that would cause all kinds of problems
in effect.
I would have broken the list structure the previous and next items the elements on either either side
of the one I've just removed would still be trying to point to the removed element and the pointer values
would continue to be the address of an element that no longer exists.
So let's look how I deal with that.
And we go back up to the function there move that function and look at the code.
So when I locate the item to be removed I have to rewire the pointers on either side so that the next
pointer in the previous element points to whatever the element I'm about to delete currently points
to.
That's what I do here.
And similarly the prev pointer in the next element needs to point to whatever the pointer in the element
I'm removing currently points to.
And that's what I do here.
And that's it.
Once I've rewired the pointers from the elements on either side of the thing I'm about to remove.
There's no longer anything in the list that points to it.
And for neatness I know said This items pointers to Nawal.
That's usually good practice though.
In fact in the present case it's not really necessary as I'm about to free its memory anyway.
And when I do that this list element of the temp structure will no longer exist.
More important is what I've done with the prev and next pointers in the struts that either side of the
deleted struct by reassigning those pointers.
So they continue to point to valid list elements.
I've maintained the integrity of the list itself.
Now let's run this and see how it works.
OK so here let me try entering three
so I've entered three and the element at index 3 that's the fourth element in this zero based list is
deleted.
But all the other elements remain in the list.
Tried again and this time I'll enter for
the last element is deleted.
I enter 0 the first element is deleted.
If I enter an incorrect index that's one that doesn't exist strike 10 where nothing is removed cannot
remove at 10 it tells me.
Now incidentally if you want to remove all elements above the certain index you can just put this code
in me just show you down here.
This code you can put it inside this loop hanging comment my loop delimiters here.
And let's try this again.
So for example I note into the index three
and you can see that matching item is removed and the next item in the list becomes the new element
index 3.
The loop executes again.
And so this element is also removed.
And so on.
Right up to the end of the list.
So you can examine the code in your own time.
If you see if you want to understand how that happens but essentially that gives us the option of either
removing one item from a specific index or that item on the items above it.