In this example I want to show how a single piece of code can code different functions using function
pointers.
I start out by defining four functions with the same arguments and return types identity just returns
the value of the arguments sent to it.
Square multiplies the argument value by itself cube multiplies it once more.
And.
Yet one small down here I declare an array of function pointers.
The PFI type is declared just as it was in my last example program this array contains the names of
my four functions.
When compiled these names are equivalent to the function addresses when the program runs.
I prompt the user to select a function from 1 to 4.
Then I ask for value.
This needs to be an integer that can be passed to one of the functions.
But first I test that the integer used to select the function is valid.
If it's less than or equal to zero that's an error.
I could test if it's greater than 4 here but who knows maybe I want to add more functions to my array
later on.
So I've written this test instead.
This has if xponent that's the function selector.
That's the integer value that user entered.
If exponent is greater than the size of the array divided by the size of a function pointer then that's
an error.
In other words it's an error if the exponent integer is bigger than the number of elements in the array
of function pointers.
When I want to call a function I call the function point array with an index.
Here I subtract one from the value entered by the user to allow for the fact that the array 0 based
in so its first index is 0 and its last is 3 and I passed the argument the value entered by the user
between parentheses here.
Well let's see this.
First of all it's a test that my tests for an invalid index are correct so zero shouldn't work.
OK it's an five shouldn't work or anything about 4.
Yep that was an error.
Now let's try the valid numbers or 1 to call the identity function for a value without it is for the
law makes sense because identity up here you can see the identity function.
It simply returns the value sent to it.
So if I enter too it should select the square function of the second function.
Here in my array Let's try the two into value.
Sure enough is squared go through those three into value because the cube function
for value it calls the full function and 256 is returned.
So they have it an array function pointers.
This allows you to code different functions selectively at runtime.