Up to now I've explained how to create pointer variables that point data items such as integers and
characters.
In fact a pointer can also point to another pointer.
So if for example you have a pointer variable called PIII that points to an integer.
You can have another pointer variable called BPI that points to the pointer variable PIII when you use
a pointer to access data stored at an address we call it dereferencing or in direction using a pointer
to access data referenced by another pointer maybe called multiple indirection.
That's because it requires more than one step more than one level of indirection to get out of the data
such as an integer character or array that is being referenced.
You may wonder why on earth you'd want to do that well multiple indirection can be used when working
with lists and arrays.
You might have lists of lists that are accessed using pointers to pointers.
We see examples of this sort of thing later in this course.
Don't worry about that panel though at the moment.
All you need to know is how pointers to pointers work.
Even if you don't use the use in your own programs you need to be able to understand them.
If you see them in other people's program.