Let's start by looking at a fairly simple example of multiple indirection here I declare an array to
store three integers where length equals three this loop.
Put some values into the array 0 1 and 2 and this loop just prints those values for me to check that
everything's correct.
Now let's see how I can access those values using both simple indirection is using a pointer to an integer
and multiple indirection using a pointer to a pointer to an integer.
I warn you in advance that simple as this may seem you'll probably need to stare at this quite a while
in order to understand what's going on.
Here are my two pointer variables p i.
Which is a pointer as the asterisk shows to an int and P PIII which as it's declared with two asterisks
All Stars is a pointer to a pointer to an int data is an array of integers as we know.
An array is an address.
It's the place in memory where a list of data items begins.
So I can simply assign not address that array variable data to my point to variable API.
Now I assign the address of PIII using the ampersand address of operator to my variable p p.
So p p is a pointer which points to the data array and PTI points to the pointer p i.e..
Now this loop iterates from 0 to 1 less than the length of the array.
That is the loop runs only while I is less than length.
In other words from zero to two and it prints out various bits of information which we look at shortly
at each turn through the loop the pointer is advanced to the next element in the array by adding one
to the point of variable P-I.
This is a simple example of pointer arithmetic which will be explained later in the course.
Now let's look at these printf statements before we do that.
Let me run the program and see the results so you can see the first print statement prints the array
address the percentage.
The format specifier is used to print an address as a hexadecimal value in address never changes of
course.
So we see the same number at each turn through the loop.
Next we dereference the int pointer PIII to display the integer at each index of the array.
The first turn through the loop PIII points to the start of the array and the first element 0 is displayed
in subsequent turns through the loop.
The other integers which we added to the array 1 and 2 are shown and now we display the item pointed
to by PBI you recall that PBI is a pointer that points to another pointer PIII we assigned the data
array to PIII.
So remember that an array is an address and at the first turn through the loop we dereference PBI to
get the value stored at whatever it points to.
It points to the point of variable PIII and that is the address of the data array.
So you can see that PBI points to p i.e. which points to the array.
The address of the array is shown here so that when we dereference PBI we get the address of the array
stored in the pointer PIII in order to go further and get the value pointed to by the pointer.
PIII.
We need to use this double indirection operator stop stop BPI says.
Get the value of what is pointed to by the pointer that p p p points to.
So Peepy I points to the pointer PIII and PIII points to an int.
So Stass stop PBI gets the value of the int pointed to by PIII at each turn through the loop API is
incremented to point to the next element of the array.
And when we use double indirection starstuff PBI that returns the value pointed to by API which is the
next integer in the array.
Now I know this can be hard to follow so let's look at this final printf statement.
This displays the address of the integer pointer variable API and the value of the pointer variable
PPA.
So when you run it you can see that the numbers are the same and they stay the same.
But it shows the value stored by the PBI variable is the address of the variable in this program.
That address never changes.
So the value of pi is the address of the thing it points to.
It points to API API points to it.
So one level of indirection stop API gets the value of the pointer PIII which happens to be the address
of an integer two levels of indirection.
Star Star PBI gets the value of PIII that is the data stored at the address pointed to by PIII.
And in this program that's the integer 0 1 or 2 at that address.
Finally add one more line to clarify this I hope even further.
Just copy and paste this in full speed
save it and run it again.
Now this line prints the value of the pointer PIII which is an address and by indirection stop by.
So there we get the integer that stored at that address the address of PIII is incremented at the end
of the loop.
So the number shown changes on each pass through the loop the value pointed to also changes to if you
look back here in the print half where we used to start before the variable.
That is two levels of indirection.
The value returned is the same value which we got when using one level of indirection with the P variable
here.
That's because Peepy I points to p.
I so one level of indirection goes to p.
I on the second level of indirection.
Goes to the integer to which P I points as I know I really know that this stuff can be really hard to
get to grips with especially if you've never used pointers or on multiple in before and you may need
to try out this code sample or write your own and maybe use a debugger to step through it one line at
a time.
It really is worth the effort though.
Once you can understand this you'll have crossed one of the major barriers to understanding how pointers
really work.