Here's another very common example of multiple indirection you'll often find that the main function
of a C program declares the argument or the preceded by two stars as you know that means it's a pointer
to a pointer to.
In this case a char the OG C argument gives us the number or count of arguments while the ARG the argument
is initialized with any arguments passed at the command line the first argument is the program name
itself on subsequent arguments.
Are any strings entered after the program name.
If you want to access the arguments you can simply treat all the as an array and print out the strings
in a simple loop and that's what I've done here.
But you could equally well iterate through the elements by moving the ARG the pointer Oggy plus because
one then using the dereference operator star on the at each turn through the loop to access the current
string.
Now let's try this out.
I should say first of all that your ID may let you enter program arguments in some dialog box Homer
for example.
In code light I can click my project name and go to settings on here in this dialog.
I can add program arguments and that can be useful if you want to set breakpoints and step through your
code using a debugger.
However command line arguments are probably best tested from the command line itself and to do that
you need to open a command prompt system prompt or the terminal window and log into the directory where
your programs being built.
In this case I'm running Windows and if I see what's in this directory and here I can see that I've
got the program executive or command line args not exit.
Obviously that would be different on different operating systems.
Now let's execute this by entering program name on its own to run the program.
And if I execute it without supplying any arguments the executive name is received as the only argument
at index 0.
Back to the code so you can compare the output with the code shown.
But now if I add some arguments in addition to that one separated by spaces 1 to three and executes.
Now you can see the output here.
So these arguments are received by the main procedure as an array that initializes the ARG the argument
and then my code parses them out into individual strings.