So far reviews are pointers to specific data types such as int and char but sometimes you may want to
write code that can deal with pointers to any type of data.
For example you may want to write some code that can sort data but you don't want to duplicate that
code by writing one function to sort Chas another function to sort integers another for floating points
and so on.
In that case you can use generic pointers instead of pointers to predefined data types.
A generic pointer is written as a pointer to void.
And when you use a generic pointer to access some data you must first cast it to a specific data type.
Here's a short example.
As in previous examples I've created an array of ints this time I've declared the point to GP to be
generic so you can see that your void star GP with no particular data type.
Now if I scroll down to see my code so here you can see I point this to the data array.
No cost is needed here as I'm not yet trying to access any actual data elements.
So the data type doesn't matter at this point.
Now here I want to print the first integer to do that.
I must cast it to a pointer to int that's in style between parentheses.
Now I use the dereference operator another asterisk to get the value.
That's the Int at this address.
And here I moved to the next array index.
And again I need to cast the pointer to a pointer to int and I print the second integer.
Here let me run this and you can see this is the output I get.
So when I run it you can see now how it actually works.
The first item in the array of ints zero is displayed.
Then after moving the pointer to the second item that is also displayed.
So that's the integer 1 there.
Close this window.
But as g.p is a generic pointer I should be able to use it with other data types not just with integers.
So let's see how I can use it with an array of strings.
Scroll up my code so you can see that I've I've actually created an array of strings here called words
and I've initialized the array with the strings 0 1 and 2.
I have already written some code to manipulate not just uncomment it down.
Right.
So now that you can see here that just as with the array of say once again set my pointer GP to point
to an array This is now the array of strings.
So you see that here G points GP points first to the array of ants up here and now it points the same
pointer points to the array of strings.
But remember that an array of strings is in effect an array of arrays of chars because each string is
an array of chars.
So when I worked with string arrays and previous examples I had to use a pointer to a pointer to char.
So here my cost has to be a pointer to a pointer to a char that's char stack style between parentheses.
Now I use the dereference operator the single star or asterisk to access the string itself.
And then I iterate to the next index again casting to char star star and finally I print the second
string and run it again.
And you can see the output.
There you see the output words array address.
First item pointed to is the first string which has the string 0.
I moved it to the next item in my code and then it was pointed to the second string which is the string
one.
So here you can see how using a generic pointer unable to access different types of data with the same
pointer and in some programs for example the data type might vary and you don't want to write repetitive
blocks of code to handle each data type.
Well that ability could be quite useful.