When I created arrays and strings in the previous examples I either declared each array all string with
a fixed length prior to initializing it like this
or I assigned a string at the time of its declaration class.
Now in either case the actual size is the amount of memory needed to hold the data is known before I
even run my program.
The C compiler is then able to set aside the right amount of memory.
So I don't get any problems for example by accidentally writing bits of data into some memory that already
contains some other data.
But what if I need to create an array at runtime.
Say for example the user enters a string at the command prompt or some data is read in promise Kyle
eyechart NO prior to compiling my code.
Exactly how much data are we dealing with.
Maybe it'll be a string containing two or three characters or it could be text from a file containing
tens of thousands of characters.
When I create an array to hold those characters or other types of data I must have some way of calculating
how much space in memory I need to hold them all.
And then I need to allocate about memory that is I need to get a chunk of memory that can hold exactly
the right amount of data only by doing that can I be sure that I won't overwrite some memory that's
already been allocated for some other data.
Memory corruption like that is a serious bag and it can cause a program to malfunction or to crash.
Now let's see how we can handle memory allocation in C..
Or start with a function that receives a string as an argument and returns a string as a result.
This function could in principle be sent many different string arguments at different points in the
program.
So it has no way of knowing in advance how long a string argument will actually be.
Of course when I say receives and returns a string.
What I mean is that it receives and returns a pointer to a char.
So I declare the function return type and the string argument as char star.
I've defined a constant mux as steel and to be 100 and within the function I've declared a variable
s to be appointed to Achang.
And as we know a pointer to a chart may also be a pointer to an array of chars or to put it another
way to a chunk of memory that stores the characters of a string.
But before I can stuff some characters into memory safely I need to allocate that memory and I do that
using the malloc function here.
I allocate 100 bytes which is enough for 100 normal alphanumeric characters this assignment begins by
initializing a string with novel which creates an empty string.
Then I use the SDR cut function to concatenate hello with the string argument and finally a new line
character and right at the end I return a pointer to the string.
And here you can see I've called this argument twice and I decided to print the return value from the
argument in this code here.
And I have used two strings of different lengths to test that the string function daz correctly with
it.
Let me run the code on.
Here's the result.
So you can see it works correctly it's allocated the correct amount of memory to deal with two strings
of different lengths.
Incidentally it's worth mentioning that malloc allocates memory on the heap.
That's important but local variables declared inside a function are allocated memory in an area called
with stack when you exit from a function.
The variables on the stock are cleaned up to all intents and purposes they no longer exist when the
function exits.
But the heap is when global data is stored in memory.
Data assigned to variables on the heap continues to exist even after you've exited the function in which
they were allocated.
So now I have 100 bytes set aside for my string.
Everything works correctly as long as I don't try to create a string that has more than 100 characters.
But what if I do need a longer string.
And there's another problem too by allocating more memory than I need.
Wasting memory in a very big program one that handles large amounts of data.
Or conversely if I'm writing a program for some sort of hardware device that has very small amounts
of memory wasting memory in this way could be a problem.
I'll explain how to avoid that in the next lesson.