Let's now see how I can allocate just the right amount of memory to hold an array containing a specific
amount of data.
Once again my program will use a string with a char array as an example.
All I want to do here is copy a string into an array.
I do this using the SDR and p y.
Function the array into which I want to copy characters is the first argument.
S sorcerer.
In other words the string I want to copy is the second argument here that's Hello.
The third argument is the number of characters that I want to be copied on.
Obviously I want that to be the size of the string.
The question is how do I calculate the size.
That's where size of comes in.
At first sight this looks like a regular C function.
In fact it's an operator and it calculates the size of the data available an array or structure placed
between the parentheses.
And of course right here is the string hello.
The value returned is an integer that represents the number of bytes required to store the data object
in this program.
I've simply used size up to calculate the number of bytes in the string.
Hello.
I've then called malloc to allocate that number of bytes to the char point s.
Notice the cost char star here.
Which is required to cast the generic pointer returned by malloc to the specific pointer type pointer
to char and for safety.
I've added this little test down here to check that the operation succeeded.
Undresses not now then.
Or being ral.
I use SDR in c.p y to copy the chaws from the string Hello into the memory location that that's referenced
by the pointer and finally just to prove the test has been initialized with the chars and is now a valid
array.
I've just used the normal array indexing syntax down here.
And here what I've done is I've changed the first character from H to C so hello becomes Chello.
There's one final point I need to mention.
You can see that I put some breakpoints here.
I put a breakpoint here and another one here.
Now that will let me run this in the debugger and examine the values of variables at these points here.
I'm using Microsoft Visual Studio because I happen to like its debugger.
But you should be able to see similar results in other debuggers.
So let me start the debugging session stop at the first breakpoint.
Now as you can see down here the value of string size is 6.
That's the variable that was assigned the return value from size of how low the string Hello.
So even though Hello only has five characters string size has the value of 6.
And that's because it includes the string Terminator Nuddle in its current.
But how can I show that.
Let me run to the next break point.
OK so since S is a pointer to char the debugger only shows me the char that it actually points to expand
airstone here shows me just the value H.
That's the first character the start of the string s.
But I only need to find the sixth char that is the one that fav characters along in memory from the
char at index 0 at the at the position the the pointer S points to Visual Studio.
I can evaluate arbitrary expressions in the immediate window down here so I can enter s and put in index
5 to see what characters actually aren't index 5 in the in my string.
And here you can see it is indeed.
No it's the terminating now.
Hence size of hello is 6 because it measures the size of the string of 5 characters that I can see a
G W O.
Plus the the null at the end.