Now if I compile this code in Microsoft Visual Studio I have a problem.
I'm told that by default see the error message.
SDR and CPI is considered to be a deprecated function and I should use the safer SDR in C.P. why underscore
Yes.
Now it is quite possible that your C compiler will complain about some functions either this one or
maybe some of those functions that I use in my code but which your compiler warns you are old that pre-created
or unsafe.
So why am I using them.
Simple answer is to make sure that my code will run in pretty much any C compiler.
Often I use the simplest most traditional functions for clarity and to ensure compatibility.
But it is true that in many cases there may be better and safer alternative functions which you may
prefer to use in your own programs.
If for example your compiler or your ID tells you that the function is unsafe you may want to stop to
look up the documentation of the recommended function and use that instead.
Or you can define the constant suggested so you can see here it suggests to disable the application.
Use this constant down here so I could copy that into my source code.
I've already made a copy ready to go and put it up here.
Saved my program and should tell the compiler to stop pestering me with error messages about the function
in question so see if that works.
Try rebuilding it goes a little think about it.
And yes so this time it seems to be quite happy.
Compile the program on there are no errors
so although there on your end say for functions that C compilers and platforms may use.
The danger is that they are going to be specific to those compilers.
The SDR and CPI underscore as function for example is provided by Microsoft but it may not work with
other compilers.
So bear in mind that my code in this course sticks whenever possible to older traditional while widely
supported functions purely for compatibility.
Even though your C system may have newer and safer alternatives and you can look those up in the documentation
and use them if they are recommended.