As well as my lawk there's another function called convoke it's often used when allocating memory just
like malloc lock clock function allocates memory but it also performs one additional step.
It clears the memory.
In other words it initializes the memory with nulls uninitialized memory contains unknown data junk
which you could accidentally try to use in your program.
If you allocate memory with Carlock a series of nodes will be written into memory until of course you
specifically write some of the data there.
If you are careful always to initialize allocated memory then by all means use malloc.
The clock function performs exactly the same function as malloc.
But in addition it ensures that the allocated memory is initialized and that allows you to test the
allocated memory if required so that you know whether or not any specific data the data that you intended
for hasn't yet been written into that memory.
The only difference to bear in mind is the syntax malloc takes a single argument which is the size in
bytes of the memory required to hold all the data you want to store clock takes two arguments.
The number of elements in the array and the size of each element.
You can calculate the size using the size of operator.
Incidentally you can also use size of with malloc if you need.
For example I could rewrite this line here which I've just got 6 as the single parameter to malloc.
I could rewrite it by calculating the size of the type which is here.
Char multiplied by size of.
That's entirely valid.
But since the simple chars just one byte in size this isn't necessary here but with other data types
such as doubles it would be needed.
So let me run my code to see how it works.
There's the results so here I just allocate memory with malloc but the memory is uninitialized.
So when my full loop iterates through it I just print out whatever random values happen to be the as
you can see all sorts of unpredictable numbers are returned.
But when I do the same thing with clock the memory that is the characters array array which my char
pointer points that's been initialized with knows.
And similarly the memory pointed to by my pointer p here.
Kulak 6.
Size of int.
Well not to has been initialized with novels.
I mean just close not.
Bear in mind that both malloc and Carlock return a generic pointer a pointer to void or a null pointer.
If the allocation of memory fails it's worth saying at this point.
What a null pointer actually is.
It's nothing more nor less than a pointer whose value is zero.
In other words whereas other pointers store a number greater than zero which is treated as an actual
address in memory.
By convention a pointer with the value 0 is considered to be one that does not point to a valid address
and we call a pointer with zero value.
Unknown pointer pointer that points to nothing and we can test for another pointer in our own code.
You can see an example here that I used in an earlier program where I test if X equals no.