In a new program that's this one in which I used my luck to set aside some memory for a string.
I allocated the memory and I left it allocated throughout my program once memory is allocated.
It's no longer available to the rest of your program.
So in principle if you continue to allocate chunks of memory you might eventually run out of memory
when there is no more memory left to be allocated.
Now on modern desktop computers this is rarely in fact the case because they simply have huge amounts
of memory.
I could go on allocating more and more memory for strings.
I never run into any problems.
Even so if you allocated very large amounts of memory without ever freeing any up when it's no longer
needed you'd be using memory very inefficiently keeping memory allocated even when it's not needed.
That is when it's no longer referenced by any variables or pointers in your program.
Well that creates what are usually referred to as memory leaks.
This could be a real problem if you happen to be writing C programs for devices that don't have huge
amounts of memory.
For example hardware controllers for machines or a Bartik devices and they might have very small amounts
of memory at any rate.
It's good practice to d allocate memory to make it available again for use in your program.
When that memory is no longer needed and the usual way to do that in C is by calling the free function
let's look at this other program so you can see this program.
I've already done that.
I've called free.
This is the program where I showed in an earlier lesson how to use the clock function and I called free
to free up memory that's no longer needed.
For example I've allocated memory for an array of 6 characters and here for six integers and then later
on when I no longer need that array I call free passing to it.
The variable for which the memory was allocated here.
That's the string s the char pointer s and here it's the pointer.
The pointer p.
You should make a habit of freeing memory whenever it's no longer needed.
But be careful if you call free on a variable that was never allocated.
Or if you try to use allocated memory after you've called free then your program will go horribly wrong.