So as a general rule never assume that you know how many bytes are required to hold a piece of data.
Don't allocate memory using a simple integer such as 24.
As shown here when you were allocating a specific number of bytes instead make a habit of using size
of Dickau collect the amount of memory needed like this but is much much safer.
The good news is when you do pointer arithmetic you can let the compiler work out how many bytes it
needs to move in order to go to the next element.
Recall that in the earlier program that I wrote here I did some pointer arithmetic with ints so I've
got an array of ints and when I added one to the pointer variable that caused the pointer to reference
the element 4 bytes along from the previous element.
And now with my struct I have a more complex data type which can take up either 24 or 32 bytes according
to how I declare it fields.
This only works by the way with arrays of specific data types you can't do pointer arithmetic with generic
pointers pointers to void unless they're first cost to a known type pointer arithmetic with fairly complex
types.
Such a struct is just as simple as with simple types such as integers adding one to the pointer variable
moves it to the next element.
That is the second element in my array of struct.
That's a great thing about pointer arithmetic.
The compiler can figure out how many bytes each element in an array occupies.
When I add one I'm not adding a specific number.
Certainly not the integer value one to the value of the pointer.
I'm telling the pointer to move one complete element along the array and that is how pointer arithmetic
works.