Now over the years when I've been teaching C programming one thing comes up time and time again it's
something that's raised by my students.
It's a struggle to understand exactly how pointers work and worst of all pointers to other pointers.
So here's an example.
Now just look at this.
This here is a pointer to an int.
The asterisk star before I.P shows us it's a pointer.
So let's look at this.
What's this then.
This one has got two stars.
Well that means it's a pointer to a pointer to an int.
And if you starting to panic at this point.
Well I've got bad news here.
It's going to get a lot worse because look at this variable.
It's got three stars and that means it's a pointer to a pointer to a pointer to an int.
How the heck are you supposed to make sense of a lot.
Well let's use the visual studio debugger.
Now you can use other debuggers Of course I mean whatever ID you are using has probably got some sort
of debugging to build 10 but I'm using Visual Studio because Visual Studio has a great set of debugging
tools.
And in this lesson I particularly want to show you how to use the memory window by the way you notice
that I grouped the pointers here inside a struct.
There's nothing special about that.
The pointers would work in exactly the same way if they were ordinary variables.
Well look I got another project down here and if I open this up you can see that here I've got the pointers
freestanding as freestanding variables and not grouped in a struct.
But for our purposes is going to be more convenient if they're placed in a struct because then they
will occupy contiguous memory locations and that's going to make it much easier for me to show you some
of the relationships between the point is when we get into the debugger and particularly in the memory
window.
Now one other thing if you want to try this for yourself I'd suggest that you compile for Win32 not
correct 64.
Again that's for convenience.
Win32 works with smaller data types and that just makes debugging a bit easier.
You can set it in Visual Studio you can set this target up you're in the Configuration Manager and you
pick whichever project you're running on and alongside it use select when.
And that's going to make sure that it can compile it as a 32 bit application.
OK so let's briefly look at what the program does.
I set I P P P to point to the address of IBP or that's actually the dot.
Here is the pointers are in a struct.
I said I Peepy to point IP and IP points to an integer.
I do which I've assigned the hexadecimal number just to make it easy to see when we start debugging.
Now I put a breakpoint here on return and start the debugger and immediately we hit a breakpoint on
the program pauses.
Now let's here we can trace our way through this set of pointers.
One way would be to go into the watch window on just a struct P and you can see that it shows some information
there which I can expand.
But that's already starting to look a bit confusing.
Just show me a bit too much information and it's quite hard for me to pick So instead of going to use
the memory window.
Now if you can't see the memory window go to debug select Windows and then you can scroll down to memory
on pick memory one to display one of memory windows.
Now at first sight here you can see the memory window.
This might look even more confusing than the watch window did because it shows a massively detailed
view of the memory that's being used.
But I can simplify that.
So first of all I right click on to get rid of all this stuff on the right which is the text display.
So I just select no text and once I've done that I need to set it to 4 byte integer and 32 bit programs
of 4 bytes is the size I need and I don't want all these columns.
I just want I got here.
I just want one column.
OK so that's tidying up this memory window display a bit.
Now I need to display the location that I am interested in.
As this is a display of memory I have to specify an address in memory so I enter the address of my struct
to my struct called P So I enter ampersand P for the address of the struct right.
So let's see what we've got here.
Let's start with this.
Here's how I got this information here.
That's the value that I entered for my Int.
I over here.
So that's helped me spot where I am in the memory.
Now on the left this is its address but look that's the same address.
This one here.
So this must be a pointer the point to i.p.
That points to Ivy and I can check that by addressing or by entering up here the address which is P
or type B.
And you can see this is the address of the IP pointer.
The value of that pointer is shown here the value is this address and at that address is my integer
here.
So that's the IP pointer pointing to my integer.
Let me go back to the it displayed my structure of the address of P.
So here I'm just being struck again.
Now let me work forward.
This time the first item in the struct P is at the same address as the struct itself.
And it is my pointer to a pointer to a pointer pointer variable contains as its value a number that
number represents an address and the number here is the first one in the right to column and it points
to this address in the left column
and you can see now why I've put these pointers in the struct by grouping them in a struct like this
I've be able to ensure that they are stored next to one another in memory and that makes it easier for
me to debug in the memory window.
OK so now this address is the pointer to another point of us IBP or is this value here.
Trace down to its values is the address of that pointer.
So the next pointer is shown here and that contains another pointer remember.
And that points to the integer.
OK so by tracing through the pointers values in the memory window we've gone from a pointer it stores
an address to the address it stores to the address that stores so on.
And eventually we've arrived at the value of the integer which is pointed to by the last pointer in
the whole list of pointers.
So I know it's quite complicated to work out multiple indirection like this but using the debugger and
in this case using the visual studio memory window you can use the watch window as well as I showed
earlier.
It should help you to understand how to peek into memory to see exactly where pointers or even pointers
to pointers to pointers are actually pointing.