Up to now whenever I want to to create a list of data items I've used an array arrays are very convenient
as they are fairly easy to use and they make it easy to get a specific element by putting an index number
between square brackets.
In many cases a simple array.
Maybe all you need whenever you want to create a new list of items but arrays have some disadvantages.
The most obvious of these is the array has a fixed length.
If I declare an array for five elements I can't add a sixth on the end of it.
Once an array is being created its size is fixed.
A workaround would be to create an array much bigger than I think I'll ever need.
So I might declare an array capable of storing a hundred elements but only initialize it with 20.
But it gives me the option of adding another 80 elements if I happen to need them.
But this is obviously inefficient.
And in any case my initial estimate might be wrong.
I might need to add 81 new elements in which case I have a problem again.
One way around this problem is to create a linked list instead of an array.
So what's the difference between a linked list and an array.
Well let's find out next.