Here's an example of a linked list of integers.
First I define a struct with fields to store some data here so simple int on the pointer.
Note that the pointer points to a data item of the same type as the struct itself called that list item.
It's my intention to create a list of struts with each struct containing or in an integer value and
a pointer to the next element.
That's the next struct in the list in my program I create two pointer variables this Ted and temp at
the start I set list head to No helped show what's going on here.
I've written this into a spreadsheet.
Here it is.
Now at the moment this is very very simple of course.
All I got here is the note that list head is equal to no simple it is at the moment.
I know that but things are soon going to get a whole lot more complicated.
So so bear with me while we look at the rest of the code.
Ok so now I execute this for loop
and what that does it creates and initializes three list items.
Allocating the correct amount of memory for each.
Using malloc and then initialize the data field of each struct to the integer I.
And that's from 0 to 2 as the form executes.
And then I assign that list head to the struts next pointer which I declared Iran and us as you know
set to No.
But let's keep track of this carefully.
So let's go back to my spreadsheet.
So at the first turn through the loop this is what we've got.
We have my struct to pointer temp pointing to a struct with data equals zero.
And it's point to the next pointer pointing to what list had points to which here is no.
Now finally in my code I've temp the temp pointer here is assigned to the list head pointer.
So Buckey my spreadsheet.
I make that adjustment.
This is not the situation we have just had points to that struct and its pointer points back to No.
Now on the next turn through the loop.
Another struct is created its data field is assigned the value 1 because the loop variable has now been
incremented to 1 its next point.
Once again points to list head which points to the last struct we created.
So in my spreadsheet we now have this
and again the list had pointer is updated at the end point to the newly created struct.
So this is how things stand now on the second turn through the for loop.
The list had pointer points to the struct containing 1 which points to the struct containing 0 which
points to know the same thing is repeated on the third term through the loop.
So we end up with something like this.
The list had pointer now parts to the last dropped we added Whose data field is to its next field which
is a pointer points to the previous struct we added Whose data field is one its pointer points to another
struct whose data is zero and its pointer points to know which is the end of the list and then you run
the program.
So I execute this while loop to trace through the list from the last item I added which is up ahead
of the list right back to the first item I added its next pointer points to now.
So I know I've come to the end of the list under loop exits.
Notice stopped in this program.
I've added each new struct to the beginning of the list.
You can of course add them to the end of the list if you prefer but it's easier and usually more efficient
to add elements.
As I have done here to the start of a list.