In this first example I'll show how to create a very simple double linked list as before I start by
defining a struct to hold some data here that's just a minute but it could be any sort of data maybe
with multiple data fields in each struct.
Then I declare two pointers to a struct of the same type one to the next struct in a list another to
the previous struct.
Notice here that I've declared two variables temp which is a pointer to struct and head which is a struct
not a pointer.
It's common practice when manipulating lists to keep track of the first element and the last element
in that list.
You could do that by defining two point variables a head pointer and the tail pointer and update those
to point to the first and last elements.
And if the list is changed by adding new elements to the start or end then those two variables would
be updated accordingly.
It's a bit neater to put those two variables into a special header structure.
I'll explain the value of a head struct in more detail in a later lesson.
But for now just keep in mind that the head struct is treated specially it's not treated as an element
of the list itself.
Here I initialize the head struct by setting both its next pointer and its previous pointers to point
to the head struct itself.
Using address of head I could set them to now but it is easier to make it point to something valid which
is itself the data field is superfluous because this struct is not a realist element.
So I set it to minus one.
Just for clarity.
Incidentally it's worth explaining at this stage why when I declare a point at the struct I have to
allocate memory for it when I declare a simple struct variable like this.
I don't have to do that.
The reason is that the C compiler knows the exact size and location in memory of a simple struct variable
at the time the program is compiled run so it allocates sufficient memory for it.
But with pointers destructs new struts can be created and deleted during the execution of the program.
Since those can come and go at runtime the memory needed is not known and can't be allocated in advance.
That's why you have to allocate memory explicitly with pointers to struts but not with simple struct
variables.
This fall loop creates some stunts.
It allocates memory and initializes the data field for each of them.
Now look how it deals with the pointers.
It should be obvious even at first sight that this is quite a bit more complicated than the code we
used to why the elements in a singly linked list.
In fact if this is the first time you've used doubly linked lists the chances are you'll need to stare
at this code and run it.
Maybe using your debugger to understand what's going on.
I look at this in detail in the next lesson.