Initializing a doubly linked list is a bit trickier than initializing a singly linked list.
Remember when I create a singly linked list I just keep adding a new struct at the front of the existing
list
and that makes it easy to initialize a pointer to point to the struct that was added previously but
with a doubly linked list I need pointers to point in both directions both the previous element in the
list and to the next element and that poses an interesting problem since of course when I add a struct
I can set its pointer to the struct on one side of it.
I like that that is to the previously added struct but I can't set a pointer to the struct.
On the other side that is the next element in the list.
Because I haven't tested it yet.
Now let's look at my code to see how I can deal with that problem.