A Q is a list in which the first thing you are is the first thing that you remove.
In other words if I create a list from eight years and I would build the list by adding a first and
last one I want to remove an item from the queue.
I take a first then B C D and so on.
Queues are typically used when you want to deal with things in a time based order.
The things that are added to the queue early on have higher priority than the things that are added
later on.
That's the way for example that your computer handles a printer queue you odd document one then document
to then documents three to the queue and the printer prints them in that order.
The first thing you did document 1 is the first thing that gets printed.
Q is sometimes called a first in first out I F.O. structure.
For that reason is a very common data structures in programming.
Another example of a Q Is the event Q maintained by your operating system.
This is the queue that keeps track of keyboard or mouse events.
A mouse move or a mouse click event is put onto the end of the event.
Q Where it waits until the operating system has time to process it.
When it does the event is pulled off the end of the queue and sent to the program that ensures that
most events are processed in the correct order so that for example if you clicked the last left mouse
button to select a cell in a spreadsheet and then you make a series of most moves each of which generates
a mouse move event.
Those events are processed in the right order.
Now if they weren't.
If for example the mouse move events were processed before the mouse click you wouldn't end up selecting
cells as you intended.
Similarly if keyboard events weren't processed in the order in which these were pressed you would never
be able to write meaningful sentences in a word processor because the characters would appear in a different
order when he entered them on the keyboard.
Q ensures that the correct order is maintained.
So your spreadsheet and your word processor work as intended.