In this next example I've adapted my double linked list so that I can use it as a cue.
There are other ways of programming cues but this is quite a convenient way of doing it.
Now this time I've defined a struct especially for the list header and the different struct for the
list elements the two pointers of the list headers struct have been given the names first and last for
clarity as before.
These two pointers.
Let us quickly get to the elements at both ends of the list.
Two really important new features of this code.
However on my end D.
Q functions and we can see these downhere NQ is used to add a new item to the back of the queue and
the queue is used to remove an item from the front of the queue.
Think of the queue like this the queue itself is a list of elements and I keep pointers to the first
element on the last element of the list.
Now when I have a new element that I want to add to the list I added to the end of the queue that is
called and queuing.
This now becomes the last element when I want to take an item from the list.
I take the first item item at the start of the queue and that's called the queuing.
So this is a bit like a line of people waiting to go into a theater or a cinema person.
Zero is the first person to arrive so person 0 is at the beginning of the line.
That is at the beginning of the queue.
PERSON 4 is the last to arrive and so goes to the end of the queue when another person arrives.
PERSON 5 they go to the end of the queue and when the doors are opened and people start to go into the
theater person at the beginning of the queue that person zero goes first.
In programming jargon 0 is de qued.
Meanwhile another person in person 6 arrives and is added to the end of the queue and in the jargon
they are encouraged.
Now I don't plan to go over the code in this program in the same minute detail as when I explained.
Doubly linked lists.
If you follow that tutorial you should be able to work out what is going on by loading and running the
queue code project yourself.
But just look at this NQ function that goes to the end of the list with the help of the head lost pointer.
It adds a new item to the end of the list assigns the new items.
Next pointer to head on the prev pointer to head last which is the previous element in the queue.
End result is that the new item is put at the back of the queue.
The dequeue function does exactly the opposite.
It gets the element at the front of the queue using head first removes it and turns it and adjusts the
pointers so that the new head first pointer points to the new first item.
That is the one following the item that had just been the qued on.
Here is the main function I can look at.
And you can see that the element that was returned by the queue is tested to ensure that it's a valid
struct and here it would be NULL if it isn't.
Because that is what dequeue return in not the case
that is if there is nothing left in the queue.
If the struct is not now I just print out its data and then free its memory.
So when I run this program you can see the result.
The queue is created and queued with a struct containing zero first and the struct containing two lost
when it's the queue.
That order is maintained the first in 0 is the first out.