In the next few videos I want to show a few examples of humbling lists in various ways.
To begin with let's see how we could count items in a list to find its length.
My example I'll once again use a q which is a doubly linked list.
Now I've written the function queue length so let's have a look at that right.
Kulang is the one that counts the elements in the list and it returns an integer the functions called
with a pointer to the list header.
That's the Q parameter here.
List header is the struct that contains pointers to the first and last elements in the list.
And as in my other examples when the list is empty the headers pointer points to the head of struct
itself.
So now I follow the headers.
First pointer.
If this points to the list header then the list is empty and the function exits.
Since length was initialized to zero that's the value that would then be returned.
Otherwise I just keep moving through the list elements using the next pointers and every time I do that
I increment this local counter variable length when I get to the end of the list.
Temp will be pointing to the header.
I then set temp to now and that provides the end condition for the do while loop so the function exits
and I return the value of the local variable length.
This simple way of iterating over the elements in the linked list can be used to do other things to
not just count them.
This is a generic technique for iterating over elements and that might be useful in all kinds of different
places when you need to do some operational calculation on all the elements of the list.
For example you may want to calculate a total of the values of a certain field in each struct in the
list.
Well all sorts of other things.
At any rate this gives you a simple way of iterating over an entire list.
Now bear in mind that this and the other examples I show in the next few videos are just some ideas
of the sorts of things you might be able to do with lists.
This is not a course about complex data structures and algorithms and there are many many more types
of list and list operations that you could come across but if you understand how to create and manipulate
lists by iterating over items adding and deleting items and ensuring that list pointers all point to
valid items in the list then you should be able to understand how pointers are used in other types of
data structure.
And you should be able to work out how to code the types of operations on lists and the elements they
contain.
Now let's run this program to see how it works.
OK so these are the results I see at the outset.
You can see that the list is empty so its length is zero.
Then I add three struts and its length is now three.
Then Id Q The queue removing items one by one and displaying the new length which as you would expect
is initially 3 to 1.
And finally when there are no more items left 0.