Another common procedure that you may need to do at some time is to make a copy of a list.
There are lots of ways you could do that.
Some ways may be simpler some more elegant and some faster than others.
I am going for simplicity since I've already implemented enqueue dequeue functions for my Q.
The easiest way for me to make a new copy of an existing queue would be to transfer the items from one
list to another by doing one queue and keeping the other.
In this example I start by creating my two queue headers SIRC is the source queue DST that's the destination
queue and I initialize the first and last pointers to point to themselves which shows that they start
out as empty queues.
Now I add some elements to the source queue.
Using my enqueue function.
By now you should be familiar with this from previous examples.
Then I run this loop to dequeue the source Q Which returns this temp element at each turn through the
loop and I build the new queue by passing the Decoud element to my end queue function calling it with
the DST.
That's the destination queue header.
I actually noticed that when I pass DST as an argument down here I precede the variable name with the
address of operator.
So I'm actually parsing the address of the DST struct but the matching parameter in my function header
we got here.
Well you can see that that is this this parameter called queue that is declared as a pointer.
In fact you will see a number of examples in my code where I pass an address as an argument but receive
it as a pointer parameter.
That's because the value of a pointer is an address so the pointer parameter is initialized with the
address that I pass to it.
Look at this.
Now finally in these two loops I call the dequeue function with the two Qs under display the result.
So let me run this now.
And this is what I see.
This shows that the elements from the source Q were added to the destination queue.
Leaving the source queue empty at the end.
Now in this example as I add the items to the destination queue I delete them from the source queue.
That's because Id queue the source removing elements and then in queueing those same elements to the
destination.
But if you want to keep the original Q intact so you end up with two copies.
You could simply iterate through the queue as I did in the previous example where I iterated over items
in order to count them instead of decreasing them.
But be careful if you do that.
If you end up with 2 queues that point to the same elements and one queue deletes an element without
informing the second queue that is done so you could create big problems for yourself because the second
Q will contain elements that point to something that no longer exists.
I have more to say about this problem when I explain deep and shallow copy in.