But if you want to add a new item to a list because it's pretty straightforward to out an item onto
the end of a list using a stock or.
Q But how about adding an item somewhere in the middle.
In order to do that you'd need to make the pointer's of the new item point to the elements on either
side of it.
So if you wanted added after element 3 then it would need its Prev and next pointers to point to elements
3 and 4.
And element 3 and 4 would also need have one each of their pointers pointing to the new item.
Only by doing that can we be sure that the integrity of the list is preserved that all the next and
prev pointers of the new item and the items on either side or point the right things.
So the list items are all properly joined up together.
That's what I do in my ADD after function.
Given a position an index into the Q and the pointer to a new element item I try to add the new item
to the existing queue this function needs to work with a queue that actually contains some elements.
So I start by checking to see that the queue is not empty.
Then I execute some code and here I iterate to the next item in the queue.
This may look quite familiar.
In fact these two bits of code are identical to the code in my queue length function.
In fact all that's different is this block of code here this is how this works.
I've set up a counter variable i.e. and on each turn through this loop I increment.
I.e. the code inside these brackets only executes when I equals position.
That happens when I moved to the array element at the desired position.
Remember position is an argument that's passed to the function.
When I arrive at that position this code requires all the pointers so that the new element here that
the struct referenced by the item pointer is inserted into the queue immediately after the item at the
specified position the item about index is here.
The struct pointed to by temp.
Let's see how it does this.
Here are the new items.
Next pointer is set to point to the next item after the current position in the queue.
Then the next pointer of the item at the current position of temp is set to point to the new item.
So if temp was Item 3 then item is now item for item 3 is next pointer.
Now point to item for an item for next pointer.
Now points to what used to be the fourth item but is now shifted one position down the queue so it's
now item 5.
OK that's fairly straightforward.
It makes sure no links are broken in one direction.
The direction that goes from element to Element via the next pointers to fix up the links in the reverse
direction we make exactly the same changes.
But this time using the press pointers.
The end result is our new item is added to the existing queue.
No links are broken at that point.
We can stop iterating through the queue as there's nothing left to do.
That's what this break Yoda's.
Incidentally when I initialize a new list element down here I set its data to the negative of whatever
index the user entered.
When the program was run there's no significance to that.
Other than that it makes it easy for us to see which element is the new N when we run the program so
let's do that now.
See the results.
At the outset the length of the queue is 5.
It contains 5 elements.
I want to add a new element after the one at index 3 q is indexed from 0.
So index 3 indicates the fourth element.
Let's try that and you can see this is what's happened.
The Q started out with five elements.
Now it has 6 and the new n you containing the data minus 3 has been added after the element added index
3.