If you've been using pointers for a while the chances are that you've already run into some problems.
The fact of the matter is that pointers are one of the major sources of error in C programs.
Trouble is a pointer can point to anything even things it has no business pointing out.
It can get it bits of memory that really shouldn't be messing about with and that can cause memory corruption
memory leaks and even catastrophic program crashes.
In this final section of the course I want to take you through a few of the most common problems you're
likely to encounter when using pointers.
These include incorrect typecasts when you cost a generic pointer to a pointer to a specific type problems
you might get if you accidentally freeze a memory that has already been freed.
Or if you try to reuse a memory after it's been freed I'll also explain memory leaks scoping problems
and why you should never dereference a null pointer.
But first I want to explain a particularly tricky subject deep and shallow copies.
Why you when you copy some data.
Say when you copy some struts from one list to another you need to be careful to understand when a copy
is a copy and why.
If you make even a very tiny mistake your program is going to end up crashing.