You may recall that when I gave an example of copying one list into another list earlier on ID cute
items from one list and included them on to a second list.
In other words I removed them from list one before adding them to list 2.
And why did I do that.
Well why didn't I just add them onto this too and also leave them in list one.
I did it to avoid having to deal with one of the common problems when copying lists when two lists contain
the same elements or other pointers to the same elements.
Any operation done to the elements in one list can have unintended side effects on the other list.
For example if I deleted an element from list to this one might continue to try to use that same element
if two lists contain pointers to the same elements.
If any of the elements in two lists contain pointers to the same data.
Then when the data is changed or freed by one list it can have unpredictable effects on the other list.
It's important to understand that there are two ways of making a copy of some data.
The first is to create a pointer to a bit of existing data.
That's called a shallow copy.
There is one little data that two pointers to it.
The second is to make a new copy of the data itself.
And that's called a deep copy.
Shallow copies are typically fairly fast because no real copying is done.
You are just creating a new reference a pointer whose value is the address of some existing bit of data.
Deep copying is clearly going to be slower because you have to get to the original data and copy it
to a new memory allocation.
Now in my short and simple programs that while it might not seem like a big deal the speed difference
would be negligible.
But in a real world program the data could be enormous.
You might need to make copies of huge arrays of complex list containing vast numbers of Stults each
of which contains large amounts of data.
So when making copies you need to be aware of the pros and cons of deep copying.
This is shallow copying shallow copies are pretty fast and efficient.
They don't mess around with the original data and they don't have to make new copies of it.
But they're inherently unsafe if you make changes to one copy.
Those changes can affect the other copy and not necessarily in a good way.
But deep copies they are safer.
They have real copies.
So when you make a deep copy you end up with two completely separate sets of data which might be contained
in arrays lists or queues at the outset.
Those datasets will be the same or at any rate and contain the same data because there are identical
copies.
But when you make changes to one set those changes won't propagate through to the other set.
If not it may not always be obvious to you when you are creating a shallow copy in some cases you might
think you are creating a deep copy but you aren't really in the next video.
I show an example in which it may appear at first sight that I've created a completely new copy that
is a deep copy of a list until I run the program and discover a serious problem.