Let's look at how to do a deep and a shallow copy of a list of struts amusing my cue program as the
basis for this although there's quite a lot of code in this example.
Well you've seen most of it before the list elements struts with the next and prev pointer's the list
header the end QUE QUE QUE Lang functions.
I've explained all of those earlier.
Here I declare three variables and they will be the header struts for three lists.
The original list and the two copies will be a deep copy.
The other a shallow copy.
Now down here
and this is where it really starts to get interesting.
Let's look first at the shallow copy this sets the temp pointer to point to the first element in the
original list.
Then allocate some memory for a new list item and uses meme's to copy the data from the original item
into the new item and it cause enqueue with the address of the destination list which is here.
Q And the pointer to the new element and q then adds the element to that Q.
Now at first sight it may seem that we now have two distinct copies.
The meme's happy wife function and other similar functions.
Copy bytes from one chunk of memory into another.
It makes an exact copy so surely my shallow copy queue should contain completely new copies of the original
Strats that's run the program and see if that's the case.
Well there's good news and there's bad news.
The good news is that yes the shallow copy queue contains the correct data.
It's a true copy of the original Q And I can see that here.
The bad news is that later on in my program when I delete the original Q.
Then try to iterate through the shallow copy queue.
I see this is some meaningless junk instead of the data.
I thought I'd copied so what's going on to help understand the problem.
I've printed out the addresses of the data in each struct in the queue and the address where that data
is stored and look in the shallow copy.
The addresses are the same as in the original copy.
So when I delete the original Q and free the memory of each of its elements the shallow copy ends up
pointing to invalid data.
Now to understand why that is.
Think about what exactly we are doing when we copy a pointer.
Let's take a look at the declaration of my list item struct that's up here.
You'll see that is data is not a simple int as in earlier examples.
This time it's a pointer to a char.
That's a very common data type.
It's the way we declare strings in C..
Now remember that the value of a pointer is a number.
It's a number that indicates the address at which some data here a char or a string is stored.
So go down here right down in this code when we created a copy using memes C.P. why the value of each
pointer was copied into the structure added to the new.
Q That means that each data item the data is the char pointer inside each struct in the shallow copy.
Q references the same memory location the same char string as the char pointer in the struts in the
original Q..
Because the value of each pointer in each copied struct is the same value the same address as the pointer
in the original struct
now.
Down here I destroy the original Q And I free the memory of the strings referenced by the data char
pointer of each struct but the char pointers in the streets in my shallow copy queue continue to point
to that data.
And that's why we end up seeing junk when I try to display the data from the shallow copy after the
original Q was destroyed.
Now let's look how I can solve that problem.
This is how I create and initialize my deep copy queue.
It starts off in the same way as my shallow copy.
I copy the data using meme's why but now look here's another step.
I use this PPI data variable which I declared earlier as a pointer to char and I allocate a new block
of memory to hold some string data.
For simplicity I'm allocating 10 bytes here as defined by the mux baffling constant.
Then I make a new copy of the string data whose address is now referenced by P data and finally assigning
the address of this new copy of the string to the data pointer of my copied struct and only then do
I call NQ to add the copied struct with its pointer now set to a new copy of the string data.
I can now safely delete the original Q and free the memory used by the struts and the strings to which
their data pointers point because my new Q..
The one that is truly a deep copy has no pointers to any data of any description from the original Q
And when I run my code again well you can see that is true that deep copy Q and all its string data
remains intact after the original Q is destroyed.
And if you look at the addresses of its data items you can clearly see why that's the case.
Whereas the data pointers in the shallow copy reference strings at the same addresses as in the original
Q While the data pointers in the deep copy reference copies of the original strings and these copies
are stored at different addresses in memory.
Bugs that result from making shallow copies can be really hard to track down.
In some cases as I've shown here you may think you're making deep copies when in fact the pointers in
the elements of the copied list point to the same data as the pointers in the original list.