So as I've said an incorrect cost can result in serious problems but sometimes incorrect costs may not
be immediately obvious.
For example look back at the generic pointer's sample program from earlier in this course.
I must admit that when I first wrote this I got the cast completely wrong.
I declared GP as a generic pointer.
A pointer to void.
And then I created an array of strings pointers to char called words and then iterated over the array
casting the GP to a pointer to char at each step like this cha style GP run I run my program expecting
it all to it correctly.
This is what happened.
In case of some unspecified error.
So what did I do wrong.
Well it turns out that I forgot that my array words was really an array of arrays an array containing
strings on strings are of course arrays of chars.
So in order to dereference the arrays of chars from within the words array I needed not one star.
As I got here.
Char style.
I needed to this chastise store just All-Starr just asked.
Also in each case those costs have to include the two stars the two asterisks not just the one.
So I corrected that mistake.
Let's rerun my code on this time.
You can see it works just fine.
So this is an example of a cost that is syntactically correct.
When I put one star char star on which the C-compiler didn't warn me about when I made a mistake.
That's because my cost specifically tells the compiler to trust me.
I know what I'm doing so I really will only use the pointers that I declare to point to what I say.
I'm going to point them to.
But in this case it turned out that I didn't know what I was doing.
That this is what I had.
So this is how I declared them previously.
I made a mistake and the compiler didn't help me to fix it.
Now that is both the strength and weakness of type casting.
In this case the compiler let me use a generic pointer as a pointer to a specific type and if the cost
is correct.
That's an extremely useful thing to be able to do but if the cost is incorrect the compiler is not going
to help me out.
It's my own responsibility.
So when you cast one type to another and especially when you cast a generic pointer to a pointer to
a specific data type you need to be very very careful that not cost is correct.