It's good to free memory when it's no longer needed.
So maybe it's twice as good to free it twice.
Well no.
As a matter of fact it isn't.
See.
Let you free memory referenced by a pointer variable.
I was many times as you like but the end result won't be good.
Bear in mind that in this tiny bit of sample code this on the other mistakes I show later on may seem
quite obvious but in a real big real world program multiple attempts to free memory may occur in different
parts of your code and they may not be anything like this obvious but the end result will be just as
bad.
So here you can see that I allocate some memory for my topline to be and here I free it twice and when
I run the program Well at first sight I don't see any problem except have a look back at my code.
So down here you can see that I call the function that includes that call twice to free.
And then at the end of the program it's supposed to print that's so folks.
But when I run it nothing.
So something's gone wrong.
It's supposed to print that text and it doesn't well that's what happens anyway with the Microsoft compiler
in Visual Studio.
That's what happens with the new compiler.
In the gcc compiler in code right now.
Well this time there's no problems at all.
Even the string displays at the end.
This is one of the things you have to bear in mind about problems like this.
Errors may vary according to the platform and the compiler and the runtime you are using and also the
compiler settings that you may have set.
Sometimes an error or a potential error may not be at all obvious on some compilers.
Well they may silently correct the error.
To save you from disaster.
Areas such as this are quite unpredictable and that makes them even harder to debug.
So it's in your interests to spot a potential error before it causes trouble.
Now let's go back to Visual Studio and this time instead of just running the code I'm going to run it
in the debugger.
Ah now this time Visual Studio warns me about the problem.
It throws an exception and it indicates that the problem is on this line of code.
The second call to free so now that gives me a chance to go and fix it.
Commented out.
Run it again in the debugger this time no exception.
There are no problems.