Memory leaks occur when you allocate memory but you don't free it when it's no longer in use.
That is when it's no longer referenced in your program.
You may think that potential memory leaks are easy to spot but that isn't always the case.
Look at this code I create and allocate some strings by allocating 10 bytes for the char pointer be
inside a loop.
Then at the end I freeby.
Well that looks OK but it isn't.
I've actually lost 90 bytes of memory.
That's because each time I set to be pointed to point to a new chunk of memory inside the loop I lose
track of the chunk of memory that I allocated on the previous turn through the loop.
Now this sort of error can be frustratingly difficult to find and fix in a big program because the syntax
is all valid.
There are no errors or exceptions thrown so there is nothing to show that I have a memory leak.
But let's now look let's run it in the debugger.
OK so I've set a breakpoint at the end of the loop so that I can watch the value B in the debug window
down here.
This shows the address first then the characters at that address.
They are random as I don't bother initializing the data here but that's not important.
It's the address I wanted to focus on Courier I'm debugging.
This shows that I must be losing the memory that I allocate because look each time through the loop
I see that memory being allocated at a different address.
Let me quickly carry on through this loop until I get to the end.
The last iteration when I was nine.
OK.
Now let's make a note of this final address 0 0 0 0 5 4 F 6 9 8.
Carry on debugging and at this point I exit the loop and I hit this other breakpoint that I set at the
end of the function.
Now when I exit the loop the address pointed to by B remains unchanged.
And it's the memory here at this specific address that's freed the memory that was allocated as all
the other addresses in the previous turns through the loop.
Well that still remains allocated and that's where the memory leak occurs.
And remember that even though B is a local variable Marlock always allocates memory globally on the
heap so that memory remains allocated even after you exit the function containing the local variable
b.