Another common problem occurs when you try to use memory that's already been freed here for example
I allocate 100 bytes for my child pointer B.
I then assign B to C and then later on I free the.
And then I decided to use my char pointer.
See I copy the string Hello into the memory to which it points.
But that's a mistake because that memory is no longer allocated.
I fried it when I called free with the B pointer.
So what happens when I run my code once again that's unpredictable.
It may cause different problems with different compilers and it might also depend on what else you've
done in your program that might have some other side effect.
All I can say for sure is that trying to use memory that's being freed is not at all a good thing to
do.
Let's let's try this out let's try first to see what Visual Studio does.
OK well this is what it does.
It keeps on printing.
C is c.
Time after time after time.
Now I've no idea why it does that.
Frankly your guess is as good as mine.
Well let's see what happens in code light.
So here I am using code like with a new C compiler GCC and Romanes Well at first sight looks fine.
Ah but now I can see there is a problem.
So in those two compilers I get two different problems.
Clearly neither is good so the problem that was hidden in my code.
The reuse of memory that is freed causes unpredictable errors depending on which compiler I am using.
Either way this is not a good thing.