While a stock could be implemented as a linked list that's not really necessary.
In fact unlike a Q or any type of linked list a stock is typically declared to be of a fixed size.
If you have a fixed size stack and you want to increase its size Well you'd need to allocate a new block
of memory and copy the existing stack elements into it.
But for the sake of simplicity I'm not going to do that.
We've already seen other data structures like linked lists and Qs whose size can be increased easily
with this example of a stock.
I'm going to assume that you will set a maximum stock size and that won't be changed my stock implementation
is a simple sequential list of elements and there are no links between them.
That is the elements don't have next prev pointers to other elements as they did in a queue.
The stock occupies a single contiguous block of memory and in that respect it is like an array.
This stock is intended to contain a fixed number of items each of a given size being quite a simple
structure.
A stock is typically faster to use than AQ and since there are no pointers between elements that means
that it can contain any type of data.
It's not restricted to working with struts that contain pointers.
Let's first consider how a stock is structured in my program.
The stock occupies a chunk of memory that starts at base.
That is the address where my base pointer points on the ends at end of my end pointer points.
I have a top pointer that's updated to point to the top item of the stock.
The stock grows in memory from the bottom upwards.
That isn't necessarily the case since then you can create a stock that grows downwards from a high address
to a lower address.
But this is the way my stock grows.
Just like a stack of plates it grows upwards as you add more plates onto it.
Now let's look at the code in more detail.