By tradition when you add an item onto the top of a stock it's said that you push it back.
I've written the push function that does that in my code here.
I first check to see if the stock has room for another item by checking if top.
That's my point at the top of the stack equals and which is the pointer to the end of the memory.
Set aside hold the stock.
You can see how these points has being assigned.
Down here in main base pointer is where the memory for my stock begins.
That's because malloc returns a pointer to the start of the allocated memory and is a pointer to the
end of the allocated memory because it's the address of base plus stock size which is a constant I defined
earlier and here that happens to be five and top the top element in the stock is here the same as base
as that isn't yet anything in this stock.
Now let's look at
so as I said I first check that there is room for a new element if the top of the stock has reached
the end of allocated memory.
Well there isn't any room otherwise this code executes.
It uses the meme's C-p y function to copy the data.
A new item which happens to be a struct at the location of the top of the stack it then increments the
top pointer.
This is another example of pointer arithmetic.
We increment top by the size of one element of the type to which top points.
And here that's a data struct.
When you take something off a stock you are usually said to pop it off.
And that's what my pop function does.
The pop function is the exact reverse of the push function.
It tests topic's base in which case there's nothing left to pop it's an empty stock otherwise it decrements
the top pointer and returns a pointer to the data struct to be removed.
Now let's go back to have another look at main
So here do.
While loop calls pop for each data item in the stock it's p data variable is a pointer to a data item.
So that lets me get at the data fields down here.
Be careful however the data in the stock has not been deleted from memory.
It's purely the pointer referencing the top item that has moved up and down.
Is this pointer that tells us where the last valid element in the stock occurs.
It would be quite possible to read data from memory areas anywhere in the stock structure between the
base and and pointers.
But if you read data in a location above the top pointer that would be an error although in some respects
creating and maintaining a stack in this way is simpler than creating and maintaining a linked list
because you have only three pointers to worry about base and on top you still need to take great care
when adding or pushing new items check that there's enough memory and when deleting and popping them
check is a valid item to be deleted and when accessing the data in an item such as the INT and double
fields a and b of my struct here I have to be sure that I use a pointer to the correct types of data
item like my PDA to a pointer to data so that you access the correct amount of memory.
Finally notice as I don't try to free up memory on an element by element basis I allocated memory for
the entire stack area at the outset and assign that to the base pointer.
When I finish with the stack I clean up by freeing base to deallocate memory block in a single operation.
I finally see this running
OK.
So remember a stock is a last in first out structure.
You can see that the last item added pushed onto the stock is the struct containing the integer and
floating point numbers 4 and 8.
And when I pop the items off the stock the last item is the one that's removed first and so on through
the entire stack one by one going through the items.
Four three two one zero.