Up to now we've looked at pointers to data of some sort.
But you could also have pointers to functions.
Function pointers are typically used when handling asynchronous events events that can happen at unpredictable
moments and which have to be able to trigger a function call to handle them.
For example you may want to call a certain function when an event fires to signal that the final document
in a printer queue has been printed.
Or you may want to call a function on a specific mouse event occurs.
Say when a menu item is clicked in your application function pointers.
While they may seem a bit obscure and it is quite possible that you may never need to use them but in
special cases they are useful and it's certainly worth knowing about them in the next couple of lessons.
I'll explain how to declare and use function pointers in C.