The syntax for declaring a function pointer Well it looks a bit odd at first sight.
Here's how I can declare a pointer to a function that takes an entire argument and returns an int he
heard the INT on the left shows the return type int in the parentheses shows the argument and test preceded
by a star is the name of the function pointer this pointer cannot store the address of any function
that takes a single argument and returns an int value.
So for example I can set test to point to the square function simply by assigning the function name
to the test variable.
I look at this in a few moments but first I want to go back to the function pointer declaration.
It turns out that I can mess up this declaration and yet it will still work.
More or less if I omit the argument it works fine.
Let's try that out.
So get rid of it int and it continues to work
attenuate with the compiler I'm using.
And if I enter the wrong argument and return types it will still compile X do that now so the function
requires an int argument and return type.
I'm going to substitute double in my pointed declaration
see if that works.
OK it seems to continue to work.
Let's try it out.
But clearly the result is not what I'm expecting.
So in short the syntax is quite tricky and some in incorrect declarations will compile and the pointer
points to the correct function but they don't work as expected.
When you actually run the program and for that reason it's common practice.
Typedef function pointers in advance.
Once you've got the correct typedef you can use the type in function pointer declarations and that should
be neater and less error prone.
Let me show you an example of typedef thing.
So I'm going to typedef.
This is the syntax for the type that iteration
right.
So this declares a type called PFI which is a pointer to a function that takes one integer argument
and returns an integer value.
Now it's easy to declare a function pointer variable let me do that.
Down here let's get rid of this confusing declaration and just put in a very simple declaration of the
type typedef at PFI.
Now I can assign the address of a function to the test variable like this and I can use the variable
name test instead of the function name because test now points to the square function.
Just check it all runs
OK so it runs on the output is correct.
Now let's look at a more complicated example in which I have an array of function pointers.