Welcome to this c course on pointer's before we get started let me say a bit about who this course is
for what you get out of it.
Now let me be clear I'm assuming you already have at least some experience of programming in C before
you start this course.
This is definitely not a course for beginners.
You need to know at least the basics of C programming syntax how to write functions parse arguments
how to edit and compile C programs.
You may also have at least some experience of using pointers but that isn't essential if you are completely
new to see where I already have another course on C programming for beginners.
And that's why you should start this course is more advanced.
It explains pointers in depth in the early stages I'll explain what pointers are and how to use them.
I'd explain addresses and in direction allocating and freeing memory pointer arithmetic and using pointers
to arrays and array elements and then go on to explain some of the more mysterious features of pointers
and memory.
Why a struct can sometimes take up more memory than the data it contains.
And why not cause problems when allocating memory.
How do you create linked lists with single or double links and how to add and delete list elements from
the end of a list or from somewhere in the middle.
I'll explain how to use punter's with specialist types such as stocks and Qs.
How to use pointers to functions or even how to use an array of function pointers.
And finally look at common problems that you experience with pointers memory leaks dereferencing null
pointers pointers out of scope errors to do with type casting and problems when making deep and shallow
copies.
If you've ever struggled to understand pointers or how to use them effectively and safely in your own
programs this is the code for you.
It covers a lot of ground and I have to admit some topics may be quite hard to grasp.
However if you watch all the lessons and use the sample source code that I provide by the time you've
completed this course you will have a deep and solid understanding of pointers in s.p.