The core learning materials in this course are the video lessons.
There are some supplementary materials too.
Most important of these is the source code archive.
The archive includes all the source code of all the examples shown in the videos.
You don't have to use code is quite possible that the video lessons will teach you everything you need
to know.
However I would suggest that you download and unzip the archive and at least take a closer look at the
code of any subjects that you find while complicated or difficult.
You can load the code into any C editor or ID and you should be able to run it with pretty much any
standard C compiler on any major operating system.
I've provided the code as Hughie's of projects that can be loaded into the free code Light editor.
If you want the simplest fastest way to load and run the code well you may want to install code right
and you can download a copy from code right.
Dot org However this is an advanced level course I'm assuming that you're already programming C.
Well you probably have your own favorite C editor that's no problem.
Just create an NTC project in whatever editor you like then load my code into a text editor and copy
and paste it into your C project.
Incidentally the programs contain a lot of comments.
So again if you need some clarification of exactly how the code works.
Reading the comments will probably be helpful if you're already a fairly experienced programmer.
You might want to skip the early lessons and go straight to some of the more advanced topics.
However bear in mind that even the early lessons helped to explain some essential basics of pointers.
Many books and tutorials on C tend to be quite vague on what the punter there really is.
They show pointers as arrows pointing to memory locations but without explaining what those arrows are
or how appointer knows where to point and it is vital to understand that these arrows were laid just
diagrams.
They don't really show what a pointer is or how it works.
Diagrams with heroes are sometimes useful undefined later in this course I'll occasionally use them
myself but they don't truly represent what pointers really are pointers.
Just a bit of data I value a number.
You really need to understand that at the outset only once you've understood what a pointer is.
Well the diagrams with all the arrows pointing to things start to make some sort of sense.
OK so let's stop.