Now let's see how we can create and use a pointer variable in C here.
I've declared a simple interfered called number and I've declared a pointer variable the asterisk store
operator shows that this is a pointer the data type shows the type of data to which this pointer will
point.
So this pointer will point to a memory location containing an integer.
Incidentally it's up to you to put the asterisk when declaring the pointer.
Some programmers put it immediately after the data type in star.
Others put it before the variable name.
So I could do this.
Leave a space after int and then put Stanham PDR.
So whichever you do they work the saying as long as the asterisk is placed between the type and the
variable name.
The declaration is valid here here I assign an interval you that's 100 into variable name and I set
the point available.
PDR to point to the NUM variable.
I do that using the addressable operator.
The ampersand in front of the NUM variable that gets the address.
Remember that's the memory location of the variable under the signs but address to the NUM PTL variable.
Let's be clear on this.
The address of operator does not return the value of the NUM variable.
That is 100.
It returns the address in memory at which that value is stored.
And if I run the program we should be able to see that this is my output.
So here you can see that the value of name variable is as expected 100.
But the value of the point available number PDR is this long.
Here here's a what is that number.
Well let's try using the address of operator and we just close this window first.
Use the address of operator here.
So I put in front of num here so when we run the code this time we're not going to see the value which
was 100.
We see the address of the variable and do it now.
Start here again.
So this now displays the address of num.
Or we can see that the value of PTO or is the address of the variable name.
Those two numbers are the same but of course just having an address of a variable is not likely to be
all that useful unless we can also find out what data is stored at that address and in the next lesson.
I'll show you how to access data.