Sometimes you may want to change the size of a block of allocated memory.
You can do that using Retallack here for example.
I've allocated enough memory to hold the string hello.
That's six bytes as calculated by size of five characters on the null terminator.
But now I decide I want to display the string Hello world.
So what do I do just increase the string length here.
And then just go ahead and print it anyway.
Or he thought works ran my program on and I just got some dumdum junk after that each time I get some
different character displayed completely unpredictable and says hello five.
Each time I run it you can see I'm getting something else some unpredictable junk that's looking around
in memory and that's because I've only allocated enough memory for hello but I tried to copy a largest
string into memory that has not been set aside to hold it and that just does not work.
I must allocate memory first but maybe I think well I can just concatenate world onto my existing string
and just comment this out first and try that out.
So I've called the function SDR caught with my string which currently contains the characters follow.
And I've tried to concatenate world onto it.
Let's run this program again and see what happens.
Even worse.
So I really messed up my program big time here by trying to cut and paste a string onto the original
string without allocating memory first.
So let me just shut this down and put my code but to use previous form.
Now since the string hello world contains 12 characters that's higher than hello one for the space Feiffer
world and one for the null terminator.
I need to allocate 12 bytes of memory and just fix this back to the correct version of the code first.
Now look down here this is where I do that re-allocation I call real cloak with the pointer to the previously
allocated block of memory which is a pointer to chawl as the first argument and the new size required
here that's 12 bytes as the second argument.
Now you can use the alc as an alternative to calling free in order to deallocate the previously allocated
memory block followed by malloc to allocate it with a given size.
See if this works.
And this time it correctly displays.
Hello world.
So the first time through it space hello because I have calculated the size of hello and then allocated
about size using malloc and the second time it displays.
Hello world.
Because I have relooked.
I called the function the new size the correct size to hold the string Hello world.
So all is well and good.
So think of reality as a simple convenient way of allocating a new amount of memory referenced by an
existing pointer.