Some of the short programs we've looked at in this course I reiterated over the items in an array just
by adding one to the point of variable.
For example here I add one to p i.e. That's a pointer to an integer in order to move to the next element
in an array of integers.
And here I iterate to the next character in a string by adding one to the PC variable which is a pointer
to char.
But wait a minute since the value of a pointer is a number that represents an address in memory.
Why does adding one to a point to have the effect of moving it to the next element in an array.
Maybe it's because it just increases the value by one byte so it moves the pointer one byte in memory
and that's where the next element in the array is stored.
But no that but simply doesn't make sense either.
I know that my C-compiler in Windows needs 4 bytes for an integer.
So I'd seen that when I add one to my pointer I actually move four bytes in memory to the next into
my array.
To understand what's really going on here we need to look at how pointer arithmetic is done in C..
Here in my address arithmetic one sample program I create an array of 4 integers since I've declared
the arrays size at the time of its declaration memory will automatically be allocated for it.
So I don't need to call the malloc function this for loop I initialize the array with four integers
from zero to three.
And I set the pointer to point to it that is by assigning the array A to the point of P I set the value
of P to the address of a.
Now let me run this code so you can see the results.
First I showed the address of the array A and the value of the pointer p and they're the same as you'd
expect then Id reference P which shows me the integer to which it points its zero.
The first element of the array the address of the array never changes.
So this number remains the same throughout my program.
Now I add one to the pointer variable P by default pointer values are shown in hexadecimal and that's
this number here.
For clarity I've also shown it in decimal format though it's possible that a compiler may object to
that.
And look even though I added one to the pointer its value is increased by 4.
So it points to an address in memory that's not one byte but four bytes further along from the start
of the array.
In other words adding one to the pointer has increased its value by the size in bytes of a single array
element and now it points to to the second element of this array.
And that's the integer 1.
Why does adding one to the pointer to increase its value by 4 is because he knows that my array contains
ints.
That's how I've declared it.
It knows it takes up 4 bytes and so it knows that when I add one to my pointer what I mean to do is
to increase the value of that pointer is to increment the address that it stores by however many bytes
are needed to move to the next element of the array.
Now I add two to the pointer and I can see that it's value the address to which it points has been increased
by 8.
That is two times the size of an int previously pointed to the second element.
Now it points to the fourth element and that's the integer 3.
And finally I decide to see what happens if I increment the pointer once again.
It already points to the final element in the array.
So what will it point to now.
Well the answer is your guess is as good as mine.
It points to whatever happens to be in the memory for bytes after the end of the array.
I shouldn't really be trying to access that memory at all.
So in a real world program you would need to check very carefully that any pointer arithmetic operations
only take you to some known memory location such as an index in an array which you have previously allocated
and initialized.