In an earlier program I showed how you can allocate a specific amount of memory here that's 12 bytes
to hold data of a specific size allocating a fixed number of bytes like this is all well and good in
a simple demonstration program but in a real world program it's a very bad idea because of the size
of data types can sometimes vary according to which compiler or operating system you are using.
Well we've already seen an example of that with a longing which has a different size on my PC and on
my Mac with more complex data types such as struts you should never assume that you know how much memory
is actually required.
Let's look at this program that uses struts here.
I've declared a struct containing two.
It's a double on the long long int.
Well I've used these data types before and I know that each end takes up 4 bytes while the others take
up 8 bytes each of them together.
I get 24 bytes.
Look I can show that this is the case by running this program and do that now
and see it.
I print out the size of my struct and it says 24.
So when I want to allocate memory for an array of my struts I just need to allocate 24 bytes for each
write wrong.
But why is this wrong.
It works after all.
We we've just seen that the program runs fine on here I allocate 24 bytes for each struct.
So what's the matter.
Well it's not so much that it's absolutely wrong for the time being in the present case as the code
stands at the moment but it is at any rate still a very very bad idea.
Let me show you why.
Let's say I decide to reorder the features of my struct.
After all C should logically come off to be shouldn't it.
So let me do that.
I'll just move B into the right position.
A B C
tidy up this very
k.
Now let's assume that I've written this program.
Tested it to see that it works as I've just done.
And then at the end of the day I just tidy up the struct as I've just done and I think no more about
it.
I send my program out into the world and when I get back to my desk the next morning everyone's going
nuts.
Why Well that's run my program again.
Here we go.
Oh
OK so we have a problem shut this down.
Some know my program and maybe in real life this would be a really important program one that runs an
international banking system or an airline control network who knows what my program now keeps crashing.
But what did I do.
I didn't change anything did I just tidy up the struct definition by reordering the features.
Well it turns out that is a change and it's not a trivial change either because strange as it may seem
my strat no longer takes up 24 bytes of memory.
So when I allocate 24 bytes I not allocating the correct amount.
This is why you should always use size of to calculate the actual size of a piece of data rather than
assuming you know its size.
So this is the problem line where I do the allocation that you replace that sort of allocating 24 bytes
the size of my struct
and run the code again.
And this time it works.
Now let's put the struct back the way it was before.
So if I move integer back into here order the struct feels
DCV and run it again and it still works.
Because no matter what the size of the struct size of returns the correct value when memory needs to
be allocated.
But I see why this program crashed when I changed the order of the fields.
This is now the struct as it was initially defined with two integer fields followed by a double and
then a long long int.
And when I print size this show this again you can see up here it comes to 24 bytes.
And that worked when I specifically allocate it as I did in my original code 24 bytes per struct.
Now if I change the order of the fields again OK.
So now we've got to double an.
And the long long int.
Now let's see what happens when I run not.
Scroll to the top and you can see the size of my structure is different.
It's now thirty two bytes.
And that's why the program crashed when I tried to add more bytes per struct than I allocated because
I'd only allocated 24 bytes.
But look the struct itself actually contains the same data now as it did before.
To lots of 4 bytes the two ints I'm two lots of eight bytes the double and the long long int and that
adds up to 24.
But it says my struct takes up 32 bytes.
When the fields are in this order.
So where are these extra bytes actually come from to understand that you have to understand how the
C-compiler lines the data in memory.