INRI This is how data alignment works.
Data Types of a certain size are aligned on boundaries of size for byte into is aligned at as it starts
in memory on a full byte boundary and 8 byte double starts at an 8 byte boundary.
If a single four byte and immediately preceding and 8 byte double as it does in my struct for extra
bytes I did after the end to ensure that the 8 by double starts on an 8 byte boundary that is at a multiple
of 8 bytes from the start of the struct with boundaries at 8 16 24 bytes and so on.
But when 2 4 byte insecure one after the other the and I could not Charile 8 byte boundary.
So the double is aligned with that boundary and no extra padding is needed and really important lesson
you need to learn from this is that the size of data types cannot be a feud with different compilers
on different architectures.
Even simple data types might take different amounts of memory.
So if you allocate a specific number of bytes when you write your code on one computer the program may
not work correctly when it's deployed on some other computer or some other device or microcontroller.
And if you use complex data types such as struts the situation becomes even more error prone the way
struts are stored in memory is not predictable across different machine architectures on its iPhone
or even making an apparently trivial change to a struct by reordering its Philo's may change the amount
of memory it needs.