Have some questions I've been asked by students I know that some programs using pointers can be incredibly
hard to understand.
Now unfortunately there's no single program that causes the same problems for everybody.
One program might be difficult for somebody to understand it's a different program might cause somebody
else problems.
So rather than give you a specific solution to a specific problem I want to show you a way of solving
point of problems for yourself using a debugger.
Now here I've picked a sample program from the code archive it's the one that goes through the command
line arguments and this one uses multiple indirection that is pointers to pointers.
Now the program itself is fairly short.
You can see I've got it loaded here into Visual Studio but it is not double level of indirection.
The **argv can be really challenging to get into your mind.
So let's see how the debugger can help us.
I'm usually using Visual Studio.
I mean just start the debugger so that you can see something happening.
Now most other good ideas with how similar tools for stepping through code and watching variables but
they may not have all the same tools as Visual Studio and a window that I like for debugging is the
one down here it's the immediate window and I'll be showing you how to use that shot.
So some of ideas may not have that but they will allow you to set breakpoints and step through your
code.
Now before we start let me remind you what Argosy is actually supposed to be in principle it's an argument
vector that's an array of strings.
Now in fact to be more accurate it's a pointer to an array of pointers with those pointers each pointing
to a string.
So let's draw a diagram to show this.
I've got Aag the
OK.
So
this is a pointer to an array draw my array down here.
And he is going to have three elements.
So the array is some address in memory and this race contains some pointers.
Two strings.
So all the points to this array and the array contains pointers to the three strings and each of those
strings is remember in fact an array of char an array of characters.
Now back to the debugger.
Whichever debugger you are using the first thing you need to do is to set one or more breakpoints.
Now I'll do that here in Visual Studio so in Visual Studio I just click in the margin and you see that
red breakpoint Mark appear a breakpoint tells the debugger to pause on a specific line to give you the
chance to look at the value of variables at that point in the program.
Now I want to understand how the ARG the argument in Maine actually works as I've already explained
óg V is an array of character arrays.
The first string is the name of the program that you are running.
If you enter any command line arguments they will also be added to the ARG V array at least to the array
to which ARG V points.
Now as I'm not actually running this from the command line I need to tell visual studio to pass some
arguments to the program.
Do that by right clicking the project node hears selecting properties going into the configuration properties
debugging on it's got this entry command arguments.
By the way if you do this I'd recommend you select all platforms it can get very confusing if you select
one platform and I compile it for another and you find that you have a different set of arguments or
no arguments at all.
So all platforms and then
these will be these will take the place of the command line arguments that I would have passed to the
program had I been running it from the command line.
OK so I'm ready to go.
So I'll start in debugging mode.
Click up here.
And when my breakpoint is hit the program pauses.
Now down here in the locals window I can see the values of variables.
First I can see that.
Argh.
See the value for óg c stores a count of the arguments where the first at index 0 is the name of the
program itself and you can see that down here is the full path.
To my program.
OK so I have carry on debugging I press 5 to carry on.
And now the breakpoint is hit again.
And that's on another turn.
Through this for loop.
So this time I see the first argument the specific argument that I entered that was the string one and
not shown alongside V here.
So what are the two asterisks for.
Now these are after all supposed to indicate that this is a pointer to a pointer.
Well look this number here gives the value of the ARG the variable its value is an address it's the
address of another pointer and it's not a pointer that points to the string.
The array of characters of a single argument.
Now I think this might be clearer if I switch to the immediate window.
Now if you can't see the immediate window you may need to activate the Debug menu go to Windows and
then down here you can see the option to display the immediate window.
Well I've already got the immediate window shown so I can start entering some things to be evaluated
in them.
Now all will remember as a pointer to a pointer to char.
Let's just enter argufy and see what we see.
OK that's the results.
So this is the same information as was shown in the locals window.
But let's break this down a bit.
First what is the address of the ARG of the variable.
Let me enter the address of operator ampersand.
ARG.
And now this is what we see.
The important bit of data here is this first number.
That's the address of the ARG the variable itself.
It's where that variable is stored in memory.
Now this stuff here.
All this between curly brackets.
This is like a full expansion of where the OG V pointer ultimately points to Daag V is remember a pointer
to a pointer to a character char star star OG V.
So let's see if we can unpick this.
Let's start with the idea that ARG V is a pointer to a pointer.
That means its value is an address that contains another pointer.
Or to put it another way the og the pointer points to another pointer.
This first value inside the curly brackets here is the address of that other pointer.
In other words the all v variable lives at this address but its value is this address an immediate window
I can see the value of a variable by entering the variable name.
So let me do that again into arguably one small plane all this time and sure enough the value stored
by the org the variable is another number another address.
So what is it the address of.
Well all being well it should be the address of another pointer.
In this case a pointer to an array of characters that is a string the string is one of the command line
arguments.
But how can we verify that.
Why do we need to dereference all the to one level.
I do that by entering asterisk all star óg the and this time I arrive at another point.
Which is at the address shown here.
And this pointer points to the string 1 the characters 0 and E form that string.
And if I want to get at the string itself I need to use one more level of direction.
I do that with Star Star OG v.
Right.
And this time I've arrived at the address of the string one.
What's stored at that address the character o the first character of the array of characters that forms
the string one the value on the left is not an address because this is not a pointer.
Hundred and eleven is the ascii value of the character.
Oh Incidentally you may be wondering how he ended up pointing to an array of strings in the first place.
That how did each of the command line arguments get assigned the pointer.
And how did those pointers get put into an array before the program even ran.
Well it turns out that the C language runtime does that for you.
There are in fact a few startup operations that go on before your program executes.
So anyway I hope this helps you understand the basics of multiple interaction how to use the debugger.
In this case the Visual Studio debug but in general how to use a debugger to solve pointer problems.
We've looked at a fairly complicated example here of dereferencing several levels.
Two levels of pointers and when you are debugging difficult pointer programs I strongly recommend that
you go into your debugger and use the sort of tools that I've shown in this video to help you understand
the relationship between pointers and the addresses to which they point.