Before we go any further you need to be sure that you understand exactly what a pointer is in many languages
languages such as Java Ruby C-Sharp and others.
You either never come across pointers or Tor or only in very special circumstances behind the scenes.
All those languages use pointers but they hide them from the programmer.
And that's because pointers can be quite hard to use and if you use them incorrectly they can cause
all sorts of errors.
In C on the other hand there's no getting away from pointers.
That's because C operates at a relatively low level by low level.
I mean it's a language that makes it fairly easy to access the operating system and the computer hardware.
On the plus side that means that you can optimize your programs to make them very fast and very efficient.
On the downside it means that C does not protect your programs from making silly or even dangerous mistakes.
And one of the commonest causes of programmer errors in C pointers so let's be clear what exactly is
a pointer.
Put simply a pointer is a variable that refers to all points to an address in your computer's memory.
Ok so now you need to be sure that you understand what Watson addresses.
Think of the computer memory as a long series of locations where bits of data stored on the location
or position in memory where some piece of data is stored is an address.
So if you want to find a specific piece of data in memory you need to find the address where it's stored.
And that's what a point does.
If you find that hard to visualize try thinking how you'd get something that's been stored somewhere
in the real world.
Imagine a long road with lots of warehouses on it.
Each warehouse contains an artifact.
I know that a specific artifact has been stored in a specific warehouse and I want you to get it for
me.
But how are you going to locate the warehouse on a road where there are hundreds thousands or even millions
of different warehouses.
Well of course I need to give you the address and here it has so I've written the address Warehouse
13 on this index card.
Now you have the address so you can go to the correct location.
And in computer terms this card is like a pointer variable.
Its value is an address by using the pointer to locate the address.
That is a precise location in computer memory.
I can access data stored at that location or alternatively I can store a new piece of data at that location.
And the next lesson will see how you would do this in a C program.