I've already mentioned a number of common problems that you might come across when using pointers in
previous lessons.
Let me start here by reminding you of a problem we've seen already namely when allocating memory you
must make sure that you allocate the right amount.
It's dangerous to assume that you know how much memory some data will require.
For example if you write a bit of code to malloc for that will work with a 4 byte integer but it won't
work with an 8 byte double.
And as I explained in an earlier lesson things can get even more complicated with straps due to the
way the data is aligned.
Change the order of fields in a struct and you change the amount of memory it needs.
Or at least you may do depending on what's stored in those fields.
For instance if you've declared a type of struct such as my struct and it contains 24 bytes of data
it would be unsafe to allocate memory like this.
That's because the actual amount of memory needed might depend on the order of the fields in the struct.
In some cases you might need more than 24 bytes of memory.
It's therefore safer to use the size of operator when allocating memory and let me change this code
to show how to do that of this and use size of my struct.
So the example that I'm showing here is found in my address arithmetic 3 sample program.
If you can't recall the details of this problem you might also want to go back and watch the lessons
on malloc and Carlock and data type alignment on boundaries.