So that's it.
You've now arrived at the end of the course we covered so many different topics punter's dresses array's
indirection allocating and freeing memory data type alignment pointer arithmetic linguists stucks cues
function pointers deep and shallow copying.
Well lots more besides.
Even though pointers are really quite simple things they can be used in all sorts of very complicated
ways.
And as I've shown in this last few lessons even simple mistakes on using pointers can result in really
serious program errors.
So where to next in this course.
I certainly haven't covered everything you can do with pointers.
Per example.
There are all sorts of complex data structures that you could create with pointers branching trees for
instance instead of linear lists under numerous searching out rhythms that can be used to find data
items in structures linked to using pointers point.
The point of this point of course is not to cover all the things that pointers can be used for.
That would make a very very long course indeed.
In any case there are lots of books and online tutorials about data structures in file handling searching
and sorting out rhythms and so on.
All of which you may use pointers.
The aim of this course is to explain exactly how pointers work.
So having completed the course you should now be able to use pointers safely in your own programs and
understand how to allocate and free memory or how to create data structures and ensure the pointers
that link together the elements of those structures always refer to point to the correct things.
In short you should have a pretty good understanding of what pointers are and how they work and you
should be able to use them correctly.
And that is one of the most important skills any C programmer can have.
A deep understanding of pointers really separates a good programmer a professional programmer from an
average programmer hobbyist or an amateur know that you have that skill you can use pointers properly.
It may of course take some time and coding practice until you've really absorbed all this information
and then it becomes second nature to you.
To do that take your time to watch videos on any topics you find especially difficult.
And be sure to use the source code supplied with this course.
The best next steps to take to deepen your knowledge is to modify some of my own code examples.
Try rewriting.
I dunno maybe to remove not just one but a whole range of elements from a list or.
Or to create stocks that grow downwards instead of upwards and then pick your own programming subject.
Something that interests you.
Disk Utility or a simple database game whatever you find interesting and use pointers in them.
Now there's no getting away from the fact that using pointers and using them well is difficult.
But now you've completed this course you've already gone far further to gain a really solid understanding
of pointers than the vast majority of programmers.
So finally all that remains is for me to thank you for putting in the time and the effort to study this
course and believe me I do know how much effort this takes.
Let me end by giving you my best wishes for your future programming career with pantos.
Lots and lots of pointers point to.