Let's now look at how pointers and addresses work and why array's especial in this program I declare
to string variables Esti all one under TR two.
You can create string variables using either syntax but you need to understand that these two variables
are by no means the same as one another.
The first SDL one declared with a pair of square brackets is an array second SDR two declared using
the store operator is a pointer as we know an array and an address or equivalent.
So Esti one is the address at which the array of characters in the string hello is stored.
But Esti are two is a pointer whose value is not the string goodbye but the address of that string.
So here are two points to the address at which the characters goodbye are stored.
This I hope should be clear when I run the program let's do that now.
So here you can see the results.
Now as you can see when displayed as an integer value the address of all one returned by the address
of operator is the same as the value of the variable as TR 1 itself.
That's because SDL one is an array and an array is in effect an address but the address of Vestiaire
to return by the address of operator is different from the value of the Esti are two variable here the
address gives us the location in memory of the pointer variable as too.
But the value of that variable is the address of the array of chars to which it points.
Let me repeat that because it's important an array variable such as Esti or one is an address.
In fact it has its own address an array variable is the address of an array but a pointer variable is
not an array it's a variable that stores the address of an array.
The pointer variable itself is stored at one address.
The array is stored at a completely different address.
Think back to the analogy I gave in an earlier lesson where I need to go to a specific warehouse on
a road containing many warehouses on my index card you remember I had the address written down.
Warehouse 13 of the index card is like a point available.
It is not the location which in our example might be the address of an array but it stores a value that
is the address that lets me find that location not swat a pointer variable does.
Now as for the warehouse itself that is the physical building we can think of that as being like our
array variable.
Its not just a reference to the location.
It is the location go back to my code and be sure that you really understand that SDL one is the location
of the start of this array of characters.
Hello.
In computer memory the address of SDL one is the location where that string of chaws begins.
But the value of the pointer variable or two is a number that gives the location of the start of the
array of characters.
Good bye.
In computer memory the address of Vestiaire 2 is the location where the SDR two pointer variable is
stored.
And if we just want to get the data in the array the address of the pointer variable itself is of no
interest to us.
The address of pointer variables will however be of interest later on.
But for now I'm only interested in the address of the array to which this pointer points the value of
SDR too is the address of the array.
The address of the first character in the string.
Goodbye.
In other words the value of the pointer variable refers to all points to the address of the array.
If you still finding this confusing try playing around with this code.
For example let's try an experiment.
I set Esti to a point available to the address of SDR one let me do that now.
The simple assignment as TR to Eco's ampersand for address of all one.
Run my program so the value of the pointer as TR to is now the address of the array.
Hello.
So as TR two can be thought of as pointing to the string.
Hello let's close down.
But instead of assigning the address the string array as TR 1 let's try assigning the array itself.
So all I have to do in order to do that is get rid of the address of operator.
I make this a simple assignment.
Let's see what happens now now well we get exactly the same results as before.
That's because as I've said before an array is an address.