Let's look at another example of multiple indirection this time with an array of strings.
Yeah I have a char pointer PC and a pointer to a char pointer PPC.
I've declared an array of words to hold a sequence of strings.
Remember that in C A string is a sequence of characters terminated by now.
So I can declare a string as a pointer to a char that is a pointer to the address of the start of the
array of characters in a string.
When I initialize a string variable or as a string element in an array C automatically appends a null
terminator to that string.
The code here assigns my PPC variabilis the pointer to a pointer to the array.
That is to the address of the start of the array.
In this for loop I iterate through the array of strings and then in this why loop I iterate through
the characters in each string printing them out one by one the outer for loop moves the PPC pointer
through the array by adding 1 to the array address here.
PPC equals words plus one.
When I say it moves the point what I mean is that the address that's the number stored by the Point
available is updated to a different address.
And we can think of this as moving the pointer because the value point available stores determines the
address that can be accessed using the pointer at each turn through the follow up.
PPC is moved to point to the start of the next string in the array.
PCI-E the pointer to char is then also moved to point to the first character of the string pointed to
by PPC.
I do this by dereferencing the PPC pointer star PPC to access the pointer PC to which PPC points.
Now this while loop executes and this runs as long as the char pointed to by P C is not known.
Remember I get it.
The char itself by dereferencing the pointer by placing an asterisk before it Star b c this printf statement
prints the current char Plus a space then the PC char pointer is moved to point to the next char in
the current string PC plus because one and I can run it and check that I get the results that I am expecting.
So here you can see that is iterated through the array of 3 strings 0 1 2 and printed them out one character
at a time separated by spaces which is what I've expected from the loops I've written.
Once again if you're new to pointers this code may take some thinking about it to understand exactly
how it works and you might find it useful to trace through your code with a debugger.
You can use whatever ID you prefer Visual Studio Net beans and so on here I happened to be using code
light debug a Windows doctor at the bottom so I could add watches and view the coal.
All sorts of other debugging tools might be available in your preferred ID either.
So let's have a look at a simple example of how I might trace through this.
I could put a breakpoint for example here on this line PC plus equals one in code light.
I just double click in the margin and it adds this little break point marker.
And now I can view the addresses and values of the pointer variables at each turn through the loops
I start the debugger and when it pauses the break point you can see that I can open up the various variable
values here in this debugger window and it shows me what the current value is like higher up tracing
through and the values change as I carry on debugging.
So in order to understand pointers because they really are quite difficult to understand when you are
learning how to use them I really advise you to take your time to write some code and use your debugger
to see how the pointers work what they're pointing out and how their values change.