In the last lesson we saw that adding 1 to a pointer cause the point to point to the next integer in
the array.
This doesn't only work with integers as long as she knows what the data type of an array is.
It's able to calculate the appropriate number of bytes needed to move from one element to the next.
Let's look at another example.
In the address arithmetic to project I've declared pointers to a variety of data types.
Int float double long long it short int and long and on each of these pointers points to an array of
the matching data type I've assigned the arrays to the pointers and fill the arrays with some data and
see them done here.
And now down here I've done some simple point arithmetic by adding one to each point to variable and
finally I print the results.
Let me run this
right.
So this is what I see when I've added one to the point of variables that's had the effect of moving
to the element at the next index of each array.
If you look at the array address and the address of the first element that is the result of adding 1
to the point of.
In each case the difference is the same as the size of the data type for fun an int 4.
For a float 8 for a double 8 for long long it to for short int for the long int you can pause the video
or run the source code yourself if you need longer to look at the decimal versions of these addresses
to see how they're incremented.
I haven't had to calculate the offset myself.
Nowhere in my code do I get the size of the data type and increment the address by that number of bytes.
C's pointer arithmetic.
When I add a value to a point of variable calculates the appropriate offset for me.
In fact on some platforms and with some C compilers the sizes of data types may be different from the
ones shown here.
I run this code just to test it out on my Mac for instance and when I did that I noticed that a long
int has a size of 8 bytes.
You can see that shown here.
Whereas on my Windows PC same long int data type has 4 bytes.
Even so I've been able to take the code that I wrote on my PC and recompile and run it on my Mac without
making any changes at all and it works correctly because the Mac compiler automatically calculates an
8 byte offset for my array of long illness.
So when I do my pointer arithmetic by adding one to the pointer variable it moves 8 bytes in memory
rather than 4 bytes as on my PC and that's how it references the next element of the array.