Now let's find out what's going on.
When I reorder the fields of a struct in the last lesson I showed that when I declare a struct with
these two integer fields next to one another the size of the struct is 24 that's equal to the total
number of bytes required by each of the four data types.
When I declare them in a different order like this.
So now the inputs are separated by the double.
No the size of the struct is 32.
So what's going on.
The answer is that the data types are being aligned in memory.
At least this is what happens on desktop computers such as.
Such as the PC that I'm using here.
But it may be quite different on other architectures such as microcontrollers to understand data alignment.
Imagine that I'm storing my struct in the matrix of cells like in a spreadsheet.
Now here's my point.
A It takes up full bytes of 4 cells in my spreadsheet.
I double B comes next.
That takes 8 bytes another c another 4 bytes and then the long long int d.
And that also takes 8 bytes these data fields arranged in memory.
Much as I've arranged them here in the spreadsheet they form a nice neat regular matrix.
Now it's not exactly the way that memory is arranged in your computer but it might be a useful way to
imagine that the fields of a struct are aligned so that they all start at a predefined boundary and
to visualize that in a spreadsheet I can start counting along the cells in my matrix of cells so each
8 byte data type needs to start at some multiple of 8 bytes in memory from the start of the matrix.
So I count the cells all the bytes used by a 1 to 3 4 but my double B constant starts here in the fifth
cell because that's on a 4 byte boundary it's where the full byte int A ends.
So I carry on counting along the four empty cells or unused bytes.
That's five six seven eight and now I've arrived at an 8 byte boundary.
Now the empty cells here on the right aren't used in fact but they are important because they help to
pad out the gap between the full byte int and 8 byte double and that's how I ensure that the double
starts on this 8 byte boundary.
So that's where it starts.
Now since I've used the clock function when allocating memory these empty cells the ones shown on the
right of the A and C it's what they've been initialized with Nos.
They don't have to be initialized that way but it's a good idea to do so and it makes debugging easier
because at least their values are predictable.
Think of this struct as occupying a matrix of 4 by 8 fulfills 8 bytes wide to accommodate the largest
data type.
That's the double and the long long int plus some padding unused bytes after the smaller int fields.
Hence my struct takes up four multiplied by 8.
That's 32 bytes.
But when I rearrange the field order by putting the two int fields one after the other so that's
like this
changes the structure of my that the layout of my structure rather to something like this.
So the C-compiler cannot optimize the structure in memory.
Instead of putting out the first field a with extra bytes it just puts the next data field which is
now another INT with the full byte.
And that's the C int.
It puts it alongside a.
And that also forms now a nice neat Matrix.
But this time no extra bytes needed to align the 8 byte data fields at 8 byte boundaries.
So the Matrix now takes eight fuel cells in my spreadsheet or eight fewer bytes in memory.
My spreadsheet now has three rows and columns three times eight.
A lot ECOs 24.
And so now my struct takes up 24 bytes in memory.
But let's go back to this version of my struct where the interviews are not adjacent to one another
so that's shown here in the spreadsheet where I've got the in a divided from C by the double B.
And then I've shown these nodes alongside.
Let me go back into my code to put the code back into that state.
So once again I've got the it's two ints separated by this double.
So let's see what happens when I run this
as the output of my program.
I've written this code to display the fields of the struct at index 0.
The first element and index 3 last element in my array this fall displays data stored at full byte offsets.
That's four bytes because that's the size of an int from the start of the address containing the struct
at index 3 the first four bytes contains the int variable a.
And if I look at the output
you can see that the value 3 the next 4 bytes is 0 that is it contains the nose that we use to initialize
the memory.
When I called Carlock to allocate the memory initially the memory contain Knowles is the painting.
These are the unused bytes between the end of the end and the start of the double and they are there
in order to line the sort of the the double tonight by boundary.
Remember we saw that represented in this way in the spreadsheet so this structure contains a mix of
data for the fields and unused bytes which here is just like that matrix in my spreadsheet.
Then we come to field B which is a double.
Stored over 8 bytes.
Don't worry what these two numbers are.
I'm displaying a decimal representation divided up into two four byte chunks of the floating point data
which occupies 8 bytes.
So it's not good to make much sense.
The actual numbers are not important.
What's important is to note that the 8 byte double fills up to adjacent four by chunks of memory so
no additional bytes were needed to align it.
Then there's another INT see its value is 60 days i.e. times 20 which I set in my code but that takes
up only 4 bytes.
So once again the full bytes have been added onto the end of it.
This is the chunk of memory that contains the nose that were added by clock and finally there's the
DeFeo that's another 8 bytes to represent a long long int.
Again the actual numbers shown here are not useful or informative as I'm showing two four by chunks
of an actual 8 byte number but that's not important for our purposes.
What's important is to see that once again no extra bytes have been added because the full 8 bytes used
and no padding is needed to line this data field.