Let's see how I can find the value of the integer to which my pointer is pointing.
In fact this variable number 2 does exactly that.
I want to assign to them to the value stored at the address referenced by the pointer variable number
TTR remember PTA points to the address ampersand dom of the NUM variable and that variable has the value
100.
Here I once again use the store operator that has an asterisk.
And when I put this in front of a pointer variable it returns not the address but the data that is found
at that address and I can now assign that data to my individual number two.
And when I run my program let's do that now.
So you can see now that I can maybe have to verify that number two has indeed been assigned the value
of was 100 to the value 100.
So in summary the pointer PDR gave me the address of the NUM variable and the store operator returned
the data stored at that address accessing data stored at an address in this way is sometimes known as
dereferencing or in direction pointer.
Gives me a reference to an address and the asterisk which is sometimes called the dereferencing operator
or the indirection operator gives me access to the data it's stored at that address.